[
  {
    "questionNum": 88001,
    "questionText": " The dewan of Travancore against whom K.Ramakrishna Pillai launched vehement criticism?",
    "answerText": " P.Rajagopalachari"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 88002,
    "questionText": " Who married Kaliyamma under the compulsion of relatives but later discontinued married life as he had been devoted to ascetic life?",
    "answerText": " Sree Narayana Guru"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 88003,
    "questionText": " Which was the major site of Kerala renaissance movements, where first major protests against untouchability and casteism in Hinduism was organized?",
    "answerText": " Vaikom temple"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 88004,
    "questionText": " In which year Pampadi John Joseph was born?",
    "answerText": 1887
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 88005,
    "questionText": " “Brahmasri Sree Narayana Guruvinte Jeevacharitha Samgraham” is written by?",
    "answerText": " Kumaranasan"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 88006,
    "questionText": " “Here I met a remarkable man” About whom Swami Vivekananda made this comment on hearing the clarifications on ‘Chinmudra’?",
    "answerText": " Chattampi Swamikal"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 88007,
    "questionText": " Sree Narayana Guru used saffron colour dress for the first time during the occassion of?",
    "answerText": " First visit to Sri Lanka"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 88008,
    "questionText": " “Reminiscences of my life” is the English translation of the autobiography of?",
    "answerText": " Mannath Padmanabhan"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 88009,
    "questionText": " Bhattarakeswaram Temple is related to?",
    "answerText": " Chattampi Swamikal"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 88010,
    "questionText": " Where Chattampi Swamikal met Swami Vivekananda?",
    "answerText": " Ernakulam"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 88011,
    "questionText": " “During my travels throughout the world, I have had the good fortune to come in contact with several saints and maharishis... But I have frankly to admit that I have never come across one who is spiritually greater than Swami Narayana Guru or a person who is at par with him in spiritual attainment.” Who paid tribute in the above words after visiting Sree Narayana Guru?",
    "answerText": " Rabindranath Tagore"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 88012,
    "questionText": " Who established Sree Vidhyadhiraja Theerthapada Paramabhattrakasram?",
    "answerText": " Chattampi Swamikal"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 88013,
    "questionText": " The publication of which newspaper was stopped in 1906 as the press caught fire?",
    "answerText": " Sujananandini"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 88014,
    "questionText": " Who among the following was a proponent of the Civil Rights Movement in Travancore?",
    "answerText": " T.K.Madhavan"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 88015,
    "questionText": " In which year K.Ramakrishna Pillai took charge as the editor of Swadeshabhimani?",
    "answerText": 1906
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 88016,
    "questionText": " Sree Narayana Guru gave the message “Organize and strengthen” during the occassion of?",
    "answerText": " Second visit to Sri Lanka"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 88017,
    "questionText": " Before his first visit to Sri Lanka what was the colour of the dress used by Sree Narayana Guru?",
    "answerText": " White"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 88018,
    "questionText": " Barrister G.P.Pillai who was mentioned by Mahathma Gandhi in his autobiography was the editor of?",
    "answerText": " Madras Standarad"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 88019,
    "questionText": " Chattampi Swamikal learnt the art of ‘Hat yoga’ from?",
    "answerText": " Thycaud Ayya"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 88020,
    "questionText": " In which temple consecrated by Sree Narayana Guru installed ‘flame’?",
    "answerText": " Karamukku"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 88021,
    "questionText": " Which eminent figure of freedom movement of India accompanied Rabindranath Tagore when he visited Sree Narayana Guru?",
    "answerText": " C.F.Andrews"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 88022,
    "questionText": " “If you want to speak of politics in India, you must speak through the language of religion.” Who gave this advice to Dr.Palpu?",
    "answerText": " Swami Vivekananda"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 88023,
    "questionText": " After the meeting which eminent personality Sree Narayana Guru wrote ‘Municharyapanchakam’(The Path of the Ascetic)?",
    "answerText": " Ramana Maharshi"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 88024,
    "questionText": " “Ascetic and holy man who tried to break the Brahmin hold on the performance of religious ceremonies. Attacked caste and associated with Izhavas. Said to have taught yoga to Sree Narayana Guru” – Robin Jeffri made this comment about?",
    "answerText": " Chattampi Swamikal"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 88025,
    "questionText": " Who wrote the article titled ‘Let’s set fire on temples’?",
    "answerText": " V.T.Bhatathirippad"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 88026,
    "questionText": " Who declared that his god and goddess are his organisation?",
    "answerText": " Mannath Padmanabhan"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 88027,
    "questionText": " Name the leader who was imprisoned in connection with Kozhanchery speeh?",
    "answerText": " C.Kesavan"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 88028,
    "questionText": " Who authored ‘Jeevakarunya Niroopanam’?",
    "answerText": " Chattampi Swamikal"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 88029,
    "questionText": " In which year Mannath Padmanabhan was born?",
    "answerText": 1878
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 88030,
    "questionText": " Sivagiri Pilgrimage begins in the month of?",
    "answerText": " December"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 88031,
    "questionText": " In which year Chattampi Swamikal was born?",
    "answerText": 1853
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 88032,
    "questionText": " The last anniversary of the SNDP Yogam which Narayana Guru attended was held at _____ in 1927?",
    "answerText": " Palluruthy"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 88033,
    "questionText": " Who is referred to as ‘Sampooranathevan’ in Ayyavazhi mythology?",
    "answerText": " Ayya Vaikuntar"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 88034,
    "questionText": " Who wrote Vrithantha Pathra Pravarthanam (1912), the first book on journalism in the Malayalam language?",
    "answerText": " K.Ramakrishna Pillai"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 88035,
    "questionText": " In 1922, when Rabindranath Tagore visited Trivandrum, who sang ‘Divyakokilam’, penned by Kumaranasan in praise of Tagore?",
    "answerText": " C. Kesavan"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 88036,
    "questionText": " Who is related to the ‘Bhagavan Karl Marx speech’?",
    "answerText": " C.Kesavan"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 88037,
    "questionText": " The date of Mannam Jayanthi?",
    "answerText": " January 2"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 88038,
    "questionText": " The lawyer who appeared for C.Kesavan in the Kozhanchery Speech case?",
    "answerText": " TM Varghese"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 88039,
    "questionText": " Who described C.Kesavan as the ‘uncrowned king of Travancore’ in a meeting held at Alappuzha after his release from jail?",
    "answerText": " K.C. Mamman Mappila"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 88040,
    "questionText": " The publication launched by C.Kesavan when the licence of Navasakthi was confiscated?",
    "answerText": " Prabodhini"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 88041,
    "questionText": " The autobiography of Swadeshabhimani K.Ramakrishna Pillai?",
    "answerText": " Ente Naadukadathal"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 88042,
    "questionText": " The name ‘Nivarthana Prakshobhanam’ (Abstention Movement) was coined by?",
    "answerText": " I.C.Chacko"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 88043,
    "questionText": " Who formed an organization named Uralungal Koolivelakkarude Paraspara Sahayya Sangham(ULCCS ) as part of his social revolutionary mission to fight the caste barriers?",
    "answerText": " Vagbhatananda"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 88044,
    "questionText": " C.Kesavan became the Chief Minister of Travancore-Cochin in?",
    "answerText": 1951
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 88045,
    "questionText": " The teeth of Sree Narayana Guru, which is his only mortal remains, is kept at?",
    "answerText": " Nerul in Navi Mumbai"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 88046,
    "questionText": " The social reformer who worked as proof reader in the publication ‘Mangalodayam’?",
    "answerText": " V.T.Bhatathirippad"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 88047,
    "questionText": " Vagbhatananda selected the city of _____ as his main centre of activity?",
    "answerText": " Kozhikode"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 88048,
    "questionText": " Who established ‘Muslim Printing House’?",
    "answerText": " Vakkom Maulavi"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 88049,
    "questionText": " The leader of renaissance who formerly worked a head loader during the construction of Government Secretariat building in Thiruvananthapuram?",
    "answerText": " Chattampi Swamikal"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 88050,
    "questionText": " Who was called ‘Pavangalude Padathalavan’?",
    "answerText": " A.K.Gopalan"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 88051,
    "questionText": " Who was called ‘Simhala Simham’?",
    "answerText": " C.Kesavan"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 88052,
    "questionText": " Along with whom Thycaud Ayya started Saiva Prakasa Sabha in 1884?",
    "answerText": " Prof.Sundaram Pillai"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 88053,
    "questionText": " Who led Rajadhani March in 1938?",
    "answerText": " Akkamma Cheriyan"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 88054,
    "questionText": " The famous journalist whose final resting place is Payyambalam in Kannur?",
    "answerText": " K.Ramakrishna Pillai"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 88055,
    "questionText": " Who established SN Trust in 1952?",
    "answerText": " R.Shankar"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 88056,
    "questionText": " Which newspaper was called ‘Bible of Thiyyas’?",
    "answerText": " Mithavadi"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 88057,
    "questionText": " Who was the first owner of Mithavadi?",
    "answerText": " T.Sivasankaran"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 88058,
    "questionText": " From where Mithavadi was published under the editorialship of Moorkoth Kumaran?",
    "answerText": " Thalassery"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 88059,
    "questionText": " From where Mithavadi was published under the editorialship of C.Krishnan?",
    "answerText": " Kozhikode"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 88060,
    "questionText": " In which year P.Krishna Pillai was born?",
    "answerText": 1906
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 88061,
    "questionText": " Who wrote ‘Jnanakkummi’?",
    "answerText": " Brahmananda Sivayogi"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 88062,
    "questionText": " The newspaper which provided propaganda for Malayali Memorial?",
    "answerText": " Malayali"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 88063,
    "questionText": " Which publication was called ‘Ezhava Gazette’?",
    "answerText": " Vivekodayam"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 88064,
    "questionText": " The social reformer in Kerala who got ‘Rao Sahib’from the British?",
    "answerText": " Ayyathan Gopalan"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 88065,
    "questionText": " Under whose compulsion C.Kesavan joined Law College Thiruvananthapuram to study law?",
    "answerText": " Sree Narayana Guru"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 88066,
    "questionText": " From whom Chattampi Swamikal learned Marma Vidhya?",
    "answerText": " Atmananda Swamikal"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 88067,
    "questionText": " C.Kesavan married Vasanthi, a school teacher, who was the daugher of the social activist?",
    "answerText": " C.V.Kunhiraman"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 88068,
    "questionText": " Who is the author of the book ‘Brahmarshi Sree Narayana Guru’ which is selected by National Academy of Letters to translate into 23 languages including English?",
    "answerText": " T.Bhaskaran"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 88069,
    "questionText": " Which occasion coincides with the proclamation of Temple Entry Proclamation?",
    "answerText": " Birth day of Maharaja of Travancore"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 88070,
    "questionText": " Who was ridiculously called ‘Kafur’ by the conservative sect of muslims as they opposed his reformist activities?",
    "answerText": " Vakkom Maulavi"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 88071,
    "questionText": " Who authored the publication ‘Treatment of Thiyyas in Travancore” in 1896?",
    "answerText": " Dr.Palpu"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 88072,
    "questionText": " The leader who had to resign from the post of Deputy President of Legislative Assmebly as he had welcommed C.Kesavan on behalf of the 51 lakh people of Travancore in meeting organised to facilitate C.Kesavan after his release from jail?",
    "answerText": " T.M.Varghese"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 88073,
    "questionText": " The famous thinker Natarajaguru is the son of?",
    "answerText": " Dr.Palpu"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 88074,
    "questionText": " Who published ‘Athmavidhya kahalam’?",
    "answerText": " Vagbhatananda"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 88075,
    "questionText": " Jatavallabhar was the teacher of?",
    "answerText": " Chattampi Swamikal"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 88076,
    "questionText": " In which branch of medicine Chattampi Swamikal acquired knowledge?",
    "answerText": " Siddha"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 88077,
    "questionText": " Under what capacity C.Kesavan attanded the Christian Conference held at Kozhanchery in 1935 and made the historic ‘Kozhanchery speech’?",
    "answerText": " General Secretary of SNDP"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 88078,
    "questionText": " The journal ‘Sivayogavilasom’ was published by?",
    "answerText": " Vagbhatananda"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 88079,
    "questionText": " Who among the following had been appointed as an accountant in Government Secretariat by Dewan T.Madhava Rao?",
    "answerText": " Chattampi Swamikal"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 88080,
    "questionText": " The birth place of C.Kesavan?",
    "answerText": " Mayyanad"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 88081,
    "questionText": " Who was passed away at Muhamma in Alapuzha district at the age of 42?",
    "answerText": " P.Krishna Pillai"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 88082,
    "questionText": " Who led ‘Oorutambalam agitation’?",
    "answerText": " Ayyankali"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 88083,
    "questionText": " The social reformer who is known as ‘Sarva Vidhyadiraja’?",
    "answerText": " Chattampi Swamikal"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 88084,
    "questionText": " Vagbhatananda established ‘Atmavidhya Sangham’ in?",
    "answerText": 1915
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 88085,
    "questionText": " The colour of dress used by Sri Narayana Guru in his last days?",
    "answerText": " White"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 88086,
    "questionText": " The founder of National Democratic Congress?",
    "answerText": " Mannath Padmanabhan"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 88087,
    "questionText": " Kuriakose Elias Chavara was beatified in?",
    "answerText": 1986
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 88088,
    "questionText": " The first Malayali poet whose picture was printed on an Indian stamp?",
    "answerText": " Kumaranasan"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 88089,
    "questionText": " The founder of Travancore Cheramar Mahajana Sabha?",
    "answerText": " Pampady John Joseph"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 88090,
    "questionText": " Which book written by Chattampi Swamikal quashes the legend that Kerala was donated to Brahmins by Parasurama?",
    "answerText": " Prachina Malayalam"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 88091,
    "questionText": " The sculptor of the statue of Ayyankali at Vellayambalam in Thiruvananathpuram?",
    "answerText": " Ezra David"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 88092,
    "questionText": " What was the real name of Anandatheerthan?",
    "answerText": " Ananda Shenai"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 88093,
    "questionText": " In which district Vaikom Satyagraha held?",
    "answerText": " Kottayam"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 88094,
    "questionText": " Who formed ‘Dharmabhata Sangham’ in order to strengthen the activities of SNDP Yogam?",
    "answerText": " T.K.Madhavan"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 88095,
    "questionText": " Who established the journal ‘Arayan’ in the year 1917?",
    "answerText": " ) Dr.Velukutty Arayan"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 88096,
    "questionText": " Who wrote a book to criticise Mokshapradeepam written by Brahmananda Sivayogi?",
    "answerText": " Chattampi Swamikal"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 88097,
    "questionText": " Who wrote a series of article in Madras standard to depict the plight of Ezhavas of Travancore with the title ‘Thiruvithamkotte Theeyan’?",
    "answerText": " Dr.Palpu"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 88098,
    "questionText": " Who wrote the editorial ‘Save the Soul of Gandhiji’ when he started fast unto death to protest against Communal Award in 1932?",
    "answerText": " Vagbhatananda"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 88099,
    "questionText": " Who organised the first fisheries Conference in 1949 with a view to evolving sustainable projects and programmes for the development of the costal region and fishermen folk?",
    "answerText": " Dr.Velukutty Arayan"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 88100,
    "questionText": " The drama written by Pandit Karuppan in connection with the ‘Shashti poorthy’ celebrations of Maharaja of Cochin?",
    "answerText": " Baalakalesam"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 88101,
    "questionText": " Who was the first Vice President of SNDP Yogam?",
    "answerText": " Dr.Palpu"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 88102,
    "questionText": " The founder of Araya Vamsa Paripalana Yogam?",
    "answerText": " Dr.Velukutty Arayan"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 88103,
    "questionText": " Another name of ‘Melmundu Kalapam’?",
    "answerText": " Channar Agitation"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 88104,
    "questionText": " Who started Araya Service Society?",
    "answerText": " Dr.Velukutty Arayan"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 88105,
    "questionText": " Who initiated Raja Yoga into Vagbhatananda?",
    "answerText": " Brahmananda Sivayogi"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 88106,
    "questionText": " Who made the inaugural speech on the All Religious Meet held at Aluva which aimed at the promotion of understanding between different religions?",
    "answerText": " Sahodaran Ayyappan"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 88107,
    "questionText": " Who founded Akhila Thiruvithamcore Navika Thozhilali Samgham?",
    "answerText": " Dr.Velukutty Araya"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 88108,
    "questionText": " The book ‘Christumathachedanam’ was written by?",
    "answerText": " Chattampi Swamikal"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 88109,
    "questionText": " The venue of Paliyam Satyagraha?",
    "answerText": " Chendamangalam"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 88110,
    "questionText": " In which year Gandhiji made a visit to Kerala, that was described by him a ‘pilgrimage’?",
    "answerText": 1937
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 88111,
    "questionText": " On whose request the proposed fast unto death by K.Kelappan was given up during Guruvayur Satyagraha?",
    "answerText": " Mahathma Gandhi"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 88112,
    "questionText": " Name the poet who named his residence as Kerala Varma Soudham as a mark of respect for Kerala Varma Valiyakoyi Thampuran, who was his close friend?",
    "answerText": " Muloor Padmanabha Panicker"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 88113,
    "questionText": " Who led ‘Mookkoothi Samaram’’?",
    "answerText": " Arattupuzha Velayudha Panicker"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 88114,
    "questionText": " Yogakshema Sabha was formed in a meeting held under the presidentship of?",
    "answerText": " Desamangalam Sankaran Namboothirippad"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 88115,
    "questionText": " The closest disciple of Sree Narayana Guru who advised the followers of Sree Narayana Guru that they should shed the concept of Sree Narayana Guru as a God?",
    "answerText": " Sahodaran Ayyappan"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 88116,
    "questionText": " Who wrote the play “Marakkudakkullile Mahanarakam” which aimed at the reformation of Namboothiri community?",
    "answerText": " Mullamangalatha Raman Bhatathirippad"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 88117,
    "questionText": " The founder of Keraleeya Nair Samajam?",
    "answerText": " C.Krishna Pillai"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 88118,
    "questionText": " Who authored ‘Keralam-Malayalikalude Mathrubhumi’?",
    "answerText": " EMS Namboothirippad"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 88119,
    "questionText": " K.Ayyappan started the journal ‘Sahodaran’ from?",
    "answerText": " Mattanchery"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 88120,
    "questionText": " The importance of 27th October 1946 in the history of Travancore?",
    "answerText": " The Vayalar uprising"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 88121,
    "questionText": " In which year K.Ayyappan was elected to Kochi legislature?",
    "answerText": 1928
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 88122,
    "questionText": " The slogan ‘Vayichu Valaruka’ is related to?",
    "answerText": " Granthasala Sangham"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 88123,
    "questionText": " The importance of 19th April 1991 in Kerala history?",
    "answerText": " Kerala bacame the first total literate state in India"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 88124,
    "questionText": " Who established Rajayogananda Kaumudi in 1911?",
    "answerText": " Vagbhatananda"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 88125,
    "questionText": " To which place in Madras province Swadeshabhimani K.Ramakrishna Pillai was banished in 1910?",
    "answerText": " Tirunelveli"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 88126,
    "questionText": " In which taluk of the erstwhile Malabar district was Guruvayur satyagraha held?",
    "answerText": " Ponnani"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 88127,
    "questionText": " Which district was the venue of Suchindram Satyagraha?",
    "answerText": " Kanyakumari"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 88128,
    "questionText": " The king of Travancore issued a proclamation announcing the right of Nadar women to wear upper clothes but on condition that they should not imitate the style of clothing worn by upper class women?",
    "answerText": " Uthram Tirunal"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 88129,
    "questionText": " Who exhorted the pilgrims not to go to Kodungallur Bharani as animal sacrifice was cruel, foolish and sinful, that the singing of obscene songs was uncivilized?",
    "answerText": " Sahodaran Ayyappan"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 88130,
    "questionText": " What threatening of Ezhava leaders made Dewan Sir C. P. Ramaswami Iyer to compel Maharaja of Travancore to issue the Temple Entry Proclamation?",
    "answerText": " En masse convertion to Christianity"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 88131,
    "questionText": " Who authored ‘Sathyamennath Ivide manushyanakunnu’?",
    "answerText": " V.T.Bhattathirippad"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 88132,
    "questionText": " The old name of Nair Service Society?",
    "answerText": " Nair Bhruthya Jana Sangham"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 88133,
    "questionText": " Who led Savarna Jatha from Nagercoil to Thiruvananthapuram?",
    "answerText": " M.E.Naidu"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 88134,
    "questionText": " Who established the first school for depressed classes in Kerala?",
    "answerText": " Ayyankali"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 88135,
    "questionText": " Who was the chairman of the Ezhava Mahasabha held at Alapuzha on 27th November, 1932 under the auspices of SNDP Yogam?",
    "answerText": " K.Ayyappan"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 88136,
    "questionText": " The publication of which journal owned by K. Ramakrishna Pillai was caesed when he assumed the editorship of ‘Swadeshabhimani’?",
    "answerText": " Keralan"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 88137,
    "questionText": " In which year ‘Kesavan Memorial’ was submitted demanding the release of C.Kesavan from jail?",
    "answerText": 1937
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 88138,
    "questionText": " Who founded Athma Bodhodaya Sangham?",
    "answerText": " Subhananda Gurudevan"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 88139,
    "questionText": " Who wrote the book ‘Dr.Palpu’?",
    "answerText": " T.K.Madhavan"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 88140,
    "questionText": " The first leader of Ezhavas to organise them into a community?",
    "answerText": " Dr.Palpu"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 88141,
    "questionText": " Who was arrested along with A.K.Gopalan when the starvation march reached Madras?",
    "answerText": " Chandroth Kunhiraman Nair"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 88142,
    "questionText": " In which year Ayyankali became a member of Sri Mulam Praja Sabha?",
    "answerText": 1910
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 88143,
    "questionText": " Where is C.Kesavan Memorial?",
    "answerText": " Mayyanad"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 88144,
    "questionText": " Who established ‘Brahma Pratyaksha Sadhu Jana Paripalana Sangham’ in 1912, aimed at the welfare of Paraya community of Travancore?",
    "answerText": " Kavarikkulam Kandan Kumaran"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 88145,
    "questionText": " The founder of Kerala Granthasala Sangham?",
    "answerText": " P.N.Panicker"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 88146,
    "questionText": " Who was the managing proprietor of Swadeshabhimani newspaper when it was confiscated by the Government of Travancore in 1910?",
    "answerText": " K.Ramakrishna Pillai"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 88147,
    "questionText": " Who led the march of volunteers from Payyannur to Guruvayur to consolidate solidarity of the general public to Guruvayur Satyagraha?",
    "answerText": " Subramanyan Tirumump"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 88148,
    "questionText": " At the time of his demise, Swadeshabhimani K.Ramakrishna Pillai was a resident of?",
    "answerText": " Kannur"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 88149,
    "questionText": " What was the destination of Begging March of V.T.Bhatathirippad?",
    "answerText": " Chandragirippuzha"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 88150,
    "questionText": " In which year Poikayil Yohannan established ‘Pratyaksha Raksha Daiva Sabha’?",
    "answerText": 1909
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 88151,
    "questionText": " Whom Ayyankali considered as his heir in the activities for the welfare of his community?",
    "answerText": " T.T.Kesavan Sasthri"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 88152,
    "questionText": " The importance of 13th May, 1935 in the history of Travancore?",
    "answerText": " Kozhanchery Speech"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 88153,
    "questionText": " Who wrote with the pen name ‘Keralan’?",
    "answerText": " K.Ramakrishna Pillai"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 88154,
    "questionText": " All Travancore Joint Political Conference was launched in?",
    "answerText": 1932
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 88155,
    "questionText": " The leader of renaissance who was known as ‘Bharat Kesari’?",
    "answerText": " Mannath Padmanabhan"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 88156,
    "questionText": " In which satyagraha, Antharjana Samajam, the women wing of Yogakshema sabha participated?",
    "answerText": " Paliyam Satyagraha"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 88157,
    "questionText": " Who founded Sidhasamjam at Vatakara in 1920?",
    "answerText": " Swami Sivananda Paramahamsar"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 88158,
    "questionText": " In which year first widow remarriage in Namboothiri community was held?",
    "answerText": " 1934 (sep 13)"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 88159,
    "questionText": " Who was the groom of the first Namboothiri Widow remarriage?",
    "answerText": " MRB (Mullamangalath Raman Bhattathirippad)"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 88160,
    "questionText": " Who was the bride of the first Namboothiri Widow remarriage?",
    "answerText": " Uma Antharjnam"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 88161,
    "questionText": " Which revolt was also called Upper Cloth Rebellion?",
    "answerText": " Channar Revolt"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 88162,
    "questionText": " In which year Parvathi Nenminimangalam was born?",
    "answerText": 1911
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 88163,
    "questionText": " Who was nominated by Cochin Legislative Assembly as the representatives of antharjanams in connection with Namboothiri bill?",
    "answerText": " Parvathi Nenminimangalam"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 88164,
    "questionText": " In which year AV Kuttimalu Amma was born?",
    "answerText": 1905
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 88165,
    "questionText": " In which year Arya Pallam was born?",
    "answerText": 1908
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 88166,
    "questionText": " The founder of Indian Coffee House?",
    "answerText": " A.K.Gopalan"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 88167,
    "questionText": " Woman leader who became the president of Malabar Pradesh Congress Committee?",
    "answerText": " AV Kuttimalu Amma"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 88168,
    "questionText": " The date of birth of Sree Narayana Guru?",
    "answerText": " 20.08.1856"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 88169,
    "questionText": " The date of demise of Sree Narayana Guru?",
    "answerText": " 20.09.1928"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 88170,
    "questionText": " Under which name the song ‘Jayajaya Komala Kerala Dharani’ is famous?",
    "answerText": " Keralaganam"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 88171,
    "questionText": " The woman leader of Communist Party who was the sister of Akkamma Cheriyan?",
    "answerText": " Rosamma Punoose"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 88172,
    "questionText": " Who is called the father of political agitation in Travancore?",
    "answerText": " Barrister GP Pillai"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 88173,
    "questionText": " Who authored ‘Sivayogarahasyam’?",
    "answerText": " Brahmananda Sivayogi"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 88174,
    "questionText": " The years in which Poykayil Yohannan was nominated to Praja Sabha?",
    "answerText": " 1921; 1931"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 88175,
    "questionText": " Who used the pen name ‘Simhalan’?",
    "answerText": " CV Kunjuraman"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 88176,
    "questionText": " The seat of Kerala State Library Council?",
    "answerText": " Thiruvananthapuram"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 88177,
    "questionText": " The motto of Kerala Sasthra Sahitya Parishad?",
    "answerText": " Sasthram Samoohika Viplavathinu"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 88178,
    "questionText": " The mouth piece of Kerala Grantha Sala Sangham?",
    "answerText": " Granthalokam"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 88179,
    "questionText": " Who wrote the song ‘Akhilandamandalam aniyichorukki...”?",
    "answerText": " Panthalam K.P.Raman Pillai"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 88180,
    "questionText": " Whose father’s name is Madan Asan?",
    "answerText": " Sree Narayana Guru"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 88181,
    "questionText": " The first branch of Theosophical Society was started in Kerala in the year?",
    "answerText": 1882
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 88182,
    "questionText": " In which place the first branch of Theosophical Society was started in Kerala?",
    "answerText": " Palakkad"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 88183,
    "questionText": " The real name of Bodheswaran?",
    "answerText": " Kesava Pillai"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 88184,
    "questionText": " In reverence of whom Vivekodayam was named so?",
    "answerText": " Swami Vivekananda"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 88185,
    "questionText": " Who was the founder editor of Sadhujana Paripalini?",
    "answerText": " Kalichothikaruppan"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 88186,
    "questionText": " Which organization established community courts?",
    "answerText": " Sadhujana Paripalana Sangham"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 88187,
    "questionText": " ‘Unaruvin,Akhileshane smarippin….’ was the slogan of?",
    "answerText": " Athmavidhya Kahalam"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 88188,
    "questionText": " In which year GP Pillai attended a session of Indian National Congress for the first time?",
    "answerText": 1889
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 88189,
    "questionText": " In which year GP Pillai passed away?",
    "answerText": 1903
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 88190,
    "questionText": " Who wrote the song beginning with the lines ‘Jayajaya Komala Kerala Dharani…”?",
    "answerText": " Bodheswaran"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 88191,
    "questionText": " Who wrote Sivasathakam?",
    "answerText": " Sree Narayana Guru"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 88192,
    "questionText": " The slogan ‘American Model Arabikkadalil’ is related to?",
    "answerText": " Punnapra-Vayalar"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 88193,
    "questionText": " Narauyana Guru established ‘Adwaithasramam’ at Aluva in?",
    "answerText": 1914
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 88194,
    "questionText": " Swadeshabhimani K Ramakrishna Pillai was passed away in?",
    "answerText": 1916
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 88195,
    "questionText": " The first Malabar political conference was held under the aegis of Congress and Home Rule League in?",
    "answerText": 1916
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 88196,
    "questionText": " In which year GP Pillai became secretary of Indian National Congress?",
    "answerText": 1894
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 88197,
    "questionText": " In which district is the birth place of C.Krishnan?",
    "answerText": " Thrissur"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 88198,
    "questionText": " Who authorered the book ‘Representative Indians’ which contains 36 biographies?",
    "answerText": " G P Pillai"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 88199,
    "questionText": " In which year GP Pillai was born?",
    "answerText": 1864
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 88200,
    "questionText": " In which year Kottayam became the fully literate town in India?",
    "answerText": 1989
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 88201,
    "questionText": " ‘Kanneerum Kinavum’ is the autobiography of?",
    "answerText": " VT Bhatathirippad"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 88202,
    "questionText": " The famous poet in Malayalam who died in a boat accident in Pallana river in 1924?",
    "answerText": " Kumaran Asan"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 88203,
    "questionText": " The son in law of CV Kunhiraman who later became the Chief Minister of Travancore Cochin?",
    "answerText": " C.Kesavan"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 88204,
    "questionText": " The venue of the first all Kerala political conference held in 1921?",
    "answerText": " Ottappalam"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 88205,
    "questionText": " With whom GP Pillai visited England in 1897?",
    "answerText": " Dr.TM Nair"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 88206,
    "questionText": " The founder of Sharada Book Depot?",
    "answerText": " Kumaranasan"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 88207,
    "questionText": " The poet who founded a tile factory at Aluva?",
    "answerText": " Kumaranasan"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 88208,
    "questionText": " Whose wife was Bhanumathi?",
    "answerText": " Kumaranasan"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 88209,
    "questionText": " In which year Kumaranasan became a member of Praja Sabha?",
    "answerText": 1920
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 88210,
    "questionText": " The first poet nominated to Praja Sabha?",
    "answerText": " Kumaranasan"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 88211,
    "questionText": " The venue of the first Malabar district conference held in 1916?",
    "answerText": " Palakkad"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 88212,
    "questionText": " The year in which Kerala Kaumudi was started publication under the leadership of CV Kunhuraman with Mooloor S Padmanabha Panicker as editor?",
    "answerText": 1911
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 88213,
    "questionText": " The year of Morazha incident in which KPR Gopalan was sentenced for capital punishment?",
    "answerText": 1940
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 88214,
    "questionText": " Who convened a conference of Buddhists in 1925and constructed a worshipping place for Buddhists near his house?",
    "answerText": " C.Krishnan"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 88215,
    "questionText": " Who constructed Paran Hall in memory of his father?",
    "answerText": " C.Krishnan"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 88216,
    "questionText": " Who introduced Education Bill in Kerala legislative assembly?",
    "answerText": " Joseph Mundassery"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 88217,
    "questionText": " Who presided over the first Malabar district conference held at Palakkad in 1916?",
    "answerText": " Annie Besant"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 88218,
    "questionText": " Who was in charge of Home department in the beginning of the first EMS ministry?",
    "answerText": " EMS"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 88219,
    "questionText": " Who was instrumental in preparing a petition named Malayali Memorial which was signed by 10038 persons?",
    "answerText": " Barrister G.P.Pillai"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 88220,
    "questionText": " Who was the editor of Kerala Kaumudi started in 1911?",
    "answerText": " Muloor Padmanabha Panicker"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 88221,
    "questionText": " “To change the Nampoothiri into human” was the slogan of?",
    "answerText": " Yogakshema Sabha"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 88222,
    "questionText": " ho said “No caste, no religion, no god for man”?",
    "answerText": " Sahodaran Ayyappan"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 88223,
    "questionText": " In order to provide opportunity of education for poor children, V.T.Bhatathirippad organised?",
    "answerText": " Begging March (Yachana Yatra)"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 88224,
    "questionText": " Ernest Kirk was the first European disciple of?",
    "answerText": " Sree Narayana Guru"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 88225,
    "questionText": " The world rises from love /And attains progress with love,/Love is itself the power of the world,/Love brings happiness to all; /Love is life itself, sir,/And Love’s absence is death”-The work of Kumaranasan which depicts the sacredness of love?",
    "answerText": " Chandalabhikshuki"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 88226,
    "questionText": " The birth place of Thycaud Ayya?",
    "answerText": " Nakalapuram"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 88227,
    "questionText": " Who wrote ‘Adwaitha Chintha Paddhathi?",
    "answerText": " Chattampi Swamikal"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 88228,
    "questionText": " Who authored ‘Baalaakalesam’?",
    "answerText": " Pandit Karuppan"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 88229,
    "questionText": " Who authored ‘Anandagurugeetha’?",
    "answerText": " Brahmananda Sivayogi"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 88230,
    "questionText": " The author of ‘Martyrdoam of Anasthasiya’?",
    "answerText": " Kuriakose Elias Chavara"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 88231,
    "questionText": " From where K. Ayyappan launched the publication ‘Sahodaran’?",
    "answerText": " Mattancheri"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 88232,
    "questionText": " To which agitation Velath Lakshmikkutty, K.K.Karumba and K.C.Kalikkutty is related?",
    "answerText": " Channar Agitation"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 88233,
    "questionText": " In which year ‘Samathwasamajam’ was founded?",
    "answerText": 1836
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 88234,
    "questionText": " ‘No to argue or win but to know and inform’ which conference is related to this motto?",
    "answerText": " Aluva conference"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 88235,
    "questionText": " Who was the exponent of Anandajathi?",
    "answerText": " Brahmananda Sivayogi"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 88236,
    "questionText": " Who was the founder of Saivaprakashika Sabha?",
    "answerText": " Thycaud Ayya"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 88237,
    "questionText": " The mission society that founded Brennen’s College?",
    "answerText": " Basal Mission"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 88238,
    "questionText": " The date on which Mahathma Gandhi and Sree Narayana Guru met?",
    "answerText": " 1925 March 12"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 88239,
    "questionText": " What type of literary work is ‘Thozhilkendrathilekk’?",
    "answerText": " Drama"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 88240,
    "questionText": " The work of Kuma ranasan that depicts the fact ‘Mamsanibhadamalla ragam’ (Love is not an artifact of flesh)?",
    "answerText": " Leela"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 88241,
    "questionText": " Who founded a school near Arppookkara for depressed classes?",
    "answerText": " Kuriakose Elias Chavara"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 88242,
    "questionText": " To which Satyagraha is Arya Pallam is related?",
    "answerText": " Paliyam Satyagraha"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 88243,
    "questionText": " When did Channar Agitation attained its objectives?",
    "answerText": " 1859 July"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 88244,
    "questionText": " Who authrored ‘Swathanthryagatha’?",
    "answerText": " Kumaranasan"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 88245,
    "questionText": " Who publised Al-Islam, the Muslim and Deepika?",
    "answerText": " Vakkom Maulavi"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 88246,
    "questionText": " Thycaud Ayya passed away in ____?",
    "answerText": 1909
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 88247,
    "questionText": " Who authrored’ Bilathi Visesham’?",
    "answerText": " K.P.Kesavamenon"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 88248,
    "questionText": " Who founded Ananda Maha Sabha?",
    "answerText": " Brahmananda Swami Sivayogi"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 88249,
    "questionText": " Who authored Vedadhikara Niroopanam?",
    "answerText": " Chattampi Swamikal"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 88250,
    "questionText": " The founder of Malabar Economic Union?",
    "answerText": " Dr.Palpu"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 88251,
    "questionText": " The first president of Purogamana Kala Sahithya Sangham?",
    "answerText": " Vyloppilly Sreedharamenon"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 88252,
    "questionText": " Who founded the organization named ‘League of Oppressed People’?",
    "answerText": " Chempakaraman Pillai"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 88253,
    "questionText": " Narayana Guru did the prathishta of the goddess Sree Sarada at Sivagiri in April ____?",
    "answerText": 1912
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 88254,
    "questionText": " Which publication was called ‘Bible of Thiyyas’?",
    "answerText": " Mithavadi"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 88255,
    "questionText": " Which publication was known as Ezhava Gazette?",
    "answerText": " Vivekodayam"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 88256,
    "questionText": " The king of Travancore who ordered for the imprisonment of Ayya Vaikundar?",
    "answerText": " Swati Tirunal"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 88257,
    "questionText": " Kuriakose Elias Chavara was born in?",
    "answerText": 1805
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 88258,
    "questionText": " Kunnampalli Raman pillai Asan was the teacher of?",
    "answerText": " Sree Narayana Guru"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 88259,
    "questionText": " ‘Land of sandal forest’ in Kerala?",
    "answerText": " Marayur"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 88260,
    "questionText": " In which district is Chinnar sanctuary?",
    "answerText": " Idukki"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 88261,
    "questionText": " The hill ditricts in Kerala?",
    "answerText": " Idukki; Wayanad"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 88262,
    "questionText": " Where is Ulloor Memorial?",
    "answerText": " Jagathy (Tvpm)"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 88263,
    "questionText": " In which district is Thunchan Memorial?",
    "answerText": " Malappuram"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 88264,
    "questionText": " Kunchan Nambiar Memorial is situated at?",
    "answerText": " Ambalappuzha"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 88265,
    "questionText": " The temple with woman priest?",
    "answerText": " Mannarassala"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 88266,
    "questionText": " Boat race related to Amabalappuzha temple?",
    "answerText": " Chambakkulam"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 88267,
    "questionText": " Boat race related to Harippad temple?",
    "answerText": " Payippat"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 88268,
    "questionText": " Ttemple is famous for the worship of Snakes?",
    "answerText": " Mannarassala"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 88269,
    "questionText": " Which temple is known as ‘the Palani of Kerala’?",
    "answerText": " Harippad"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 88270,
    "questionText": " Which is known as ‘bird village in Kerala’?",
    "answerText": " Nooranad"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 88271,
    "questionText": " Who called Alappuzha ‘Venice of the East’ for the first time?",
    "answerText": " Lord Curzon"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 88272,
    "questionText": " An ancient Buddhist centre in Alapuzha distirict?",
    "answerText": " Srimulavasam"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 88273,
    "questionText": " The place where Parthasarathy Temple is situated?",
    "answerText": " Aranmula"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 88274,
    "questionText": " The temple known as ‘Dakshina Mookambi’?",
    "answerText": " Panchikkad"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 88275,
    "questionText": " Wagon Tragedy Memorial Hall is situated at?",
    "answerText": " Tirur"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 88276,
    "questionText": " Changampuzha memorial is situated at?",
    "answerText": " Edappally"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 88277,
    "questionText": " Kondoty, where Moyinkutty Vaidyar Memorial is situated is in the district of?",
    "answerText": " Malappuram"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 88278,
    "questionText": " P Kunjiraman Nair memorial is at?",
    "answerText": " Kollengode"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 88279,
    "questionText": " Muloor S Padamanabha Panikker memorial is at?",
    "answerText": " Ilavumthitta"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 88280,
    "questionText": " Murajapam in Padmanabha Swami Temple is held every ... ?",
    "answerText": " 6 years"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 88281,
    "questionText": " The radio station in Travancore started functioning in?",
    "answerText": 1943
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 88282,
    "questionText": " The place in Thiruvananthapuram district from where Graphite ore is obtained?",
    "answerText": " Vellanad"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 88283,
    "questionText": " The district that is the largest producer of Tapioca?",
    "answerText": " Thiruvananthapuram"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 88284,
    "questionText": " In which district is Ponmudi hill station?",
    "answerText": " Thiruvananthapuram"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 88285,
    "questionText": " The MC Road and NH 47 meet at?",
    "answerText": " Kesavadasapuram"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 88286,
    "questionText": " Where is Papanasam beach?",
    "answerText": " Varkala"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 88287,
    "questionText": " During the period of Swati Tirunal, the Hajur Kacheri (Secretariat) of Travancore was shifted to Thiruvananthapuram from?",
    "answerText": " Kollam"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 88288,
    "questionText": " Ceramic Factory in Kerala is situated at?",
    "answerText": " Kundara"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 88289,
    "questionText": " M.C.Road connects Thiruvananthapuram and ........ ?",
    "answerText": " Angamali"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 88290,
    "questionText": " The king who shifted the capital of Travancore from Padmanabhapuram to Thiruvanananthapuram?",
    "answerText": " Dharma Raja"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 88291,
    "questionText": " In 1869, a new secretariat building was constructed in Thiruvananthapuram during the reign of Ayilyam Tirunal under the supervision of Dewan ...... ?",
    "answerText": " T.Madhava Rao"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 88292,
    "questionText": " In 1888, the legislative council in Travancore started functioning at?",
    "answerText": " Thiruvananthapuram"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 88293,
    "questionText": " The Kollam - Kottappuram strech of West Coast Canal is known as?",
    "answerText": " National Waterway-3"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 88294,
    "questionText": " The place in Kerala where China clay is abundant?",
    "answerText": " Kundara"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 88295,
    "questionText": " The seat of Ilayidathu swaroopam in Travancore history was?",
    "answerText": " Kottarakkara"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 88296,
    "questionText": " Vallikkavu, where the Ashram of Amritanandamayi is situated is in the district of?",
    "answerText": " Kollam"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 88297,
    "questionText": " Which of the following place in Kerala is famous for cashew industry?",
    "answerText": " Kollam"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 88298,
    "questionText": " The famous statue in front of the Govt. Secretariat, Thiruvananthapuram from which the name ‘Statue Junction’ is evolved, is that of?",
    "answerText": " Madhava Rao"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 88299,
    "questionText": " The southernmost taluk in Kerala?",
    "answerText": " Neyyatinkara"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 88300,
    "questionText": " Where is Lakshmi Bhai College of Physical Education?",
    "answerText": " Karyavattom"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 88301,
    "questionText": " In which district is Neyyar Wild Life Sanctuary?",
    "answerText": " Thiruvananthapuram"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 88302,
    "questionText": " The highest peak in Thiruvananthapuram district?",
    "answerText": " Agasthyamala"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 88303,
    "questionText": " In which distict the Shendurney wild life sanctuary is situated?",
    "answerText": " Kollam"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 88304,
    "questionText": " The Alapuzha district was formed in 1957 mainly by the bifurcation of?",
    "answerText": " Kollam"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 88305,
    "questionText": " Neendakara Azhi connects ...... and Arabian sea?",
    "answerText": " Ashtamudi lake"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 88306,
    "questionText": " MN Govindan Nair started One Lakh Housing Scheme at?",
    "answerText": " Chithara"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 88307,
    "questionText": " The place where Duryodhana Temple is situated in Kollam district?",
    "answerText": " Malanada"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 88308,
    "questionText": " The district with least coastline?",
    "answerText": " Kollam"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 88309,
    "questionText": " The only district in South Kerala without coastline?",
    "answerText": " Pathanamthitta"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 88310,
    "questionText": " Which boat race is known as ‘Pooram in Water’?",
    "answerText": " Aranmula boat race"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 88311,
    "questionText": " Which was the capital of the kingdom of Chempakassery?",
    "answerText": " Ambalappuzha"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 88312,
    "questionText": " An area in Kerala which is situated below sea level?",
    "answerText": " Kuttanad"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 88313,
    "questionText": " Karumadikkuttan, a statue obtained from Alappuzha district is believed to be related to?",
    "answerText": " Buddhism"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 88314,
    "questionText": " Where is Chinnakkada ground situated?",
    "answerText": " Kollam"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 88315,
    "questionText": " The substance used to make Aranmula mirror?",
    "answerText": " Metal"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 88316,
    "questionText": " The place where ‘Chilanthi temple’ situated in Pathanamthitta district?",
    "answerText": " Kodumon"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 88317,
    "questionText": " Mannadi, the place where Velu Thampy Dalawa committed suicide is in the district of?",
    "answerText": " Pathanamthitta"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 88318,
    "questionText": " The season of Sabarimala pilgrimage?",
    "answerText": " November- January"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 88319,
    "questionText": " In which month Maramon Convention is conducted on the banks of Pamba?",
    "answerText": " February"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 88320,
    "questionText": " Where is Kunjan Memorial in Palghat district?",
    "answerText": " Lakkadi"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 88321,
    "questionText": " Whose memorial is situated at Kotayi in Palakkad district?",
    "answerText": " Chembai Vaidhyanatha Bhagavathar"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 88322,
    "questionText": " What is known as ‘Dakshina Nalanda’?",
    "answerText": " Kanthallur Sala"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 88323,
    "questionText": " The area known as the ‘granary of Travancore’, which is now in Kanyakumari district?",
    "answerText": " Nanjinad"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 88324,
    "questionText": " Birth place of Saktibhadra, the author of ‘Ascharyachoodamani’?",
    "answerText": " Kodumo"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 88325,
    "questionText": " Padayani is the folk arts form of the district of?",
    "answerText": " Pathanamthitta"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 88326,
    "questionText": " The only railway station in Pathanamthitta district?",
    "answerText": " Thiruvalla"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 88327,
    "questionText": " The boat race which held on the second Saturday of August every year?",
    "answerText": " Nehru Trophy"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 88328,
    "questionText": " Thycal, where remains of of an ancient ship obtained is in the district of?",
    "answerText": " Alappuzha"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 88329,
    "questionText": " The area in Kerala that receives least rain fall?",
    "answerText": " Chinnar"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 88330,
    "questionText": " The island formed after the dredging activities of the Cochin port?",
    "answerText": " Wellington"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 88331,
    "questionText": " The place related to Athachamayam?",
    "answerText": " Thrikkakkara"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 88332,
    "questionText": " In which district Nedumbassery air port is situated?",
    "answerText": " Ernakulam"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 88333,
    "questionText": " In which district is Brahmapuram diesel project?",
    "answerText": " Ernakulam"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 88334,
    "questionText": " The headquarters of the Dutch territories in Kerala during the colonial regime was?",
    "answerText": " Kochi"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 88335,
    "questionText": " In which district is Kodanad elephant training centre?",
    "answerText": " Ernakulam"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 88336,
    "questionText": " The only major port in Kerala?",
    "answerText": " Kochi"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 88337,
    "questionText": " The port in Kerala which was developed by Robert Bristo into a major port?",
    "answerText": " Kochi"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 88338,
    "questionText": " In which district is Bhutathankettu?",
    "answerText": " Ernakulam"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 88339,
    "questionText": " In which district is Mangalavanam sanctuary situated?",
    "answerText": " Ernakulam"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 88340,
    "questionText": " Nehru Trophy Boat race is in?",
    "answerText": " Punnamada"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 88341,
    "questionText": " The church where Vasco da Gama was buried at Kochi. ?",
    "answerText": " St. Francis Church"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 88342,
    "questionText": " The place in Kerala where St.Thomas landed in AD52?",
    "answerText": " Malyankara"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 88343,
    "questionText": " The International Stadium at Kaloor in Ernakulam district is named after?",
    "answerText": " Jawaharlal Nehru"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 88344,
    "questionText": " Aluva in Ernakulam is famous for ....... celebration.?",
    "answerText": " Sivarathri"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 88345,
    "questionText": " The place known as the ‘Gateway to high range’?",
    "answerText": " Kothamangalam"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 88346,
    "questionText": " Which is known as ‘the green lungs of Kochi’?",
    "answerText": " Mangalavanam"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 88347,
    "questionText": " In which district is Mooriyad lake?",
    "answerText": " Thrissur"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 88348,
    "questionText": " In which district Peechi dam is situated?",
    "answerText": " Thrissur"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 88349,
    "questionText": " The place where an observatory was established in ancient Kerala?",
    "answerText": " Mahodayapuram"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 88350,
    "questionText": " The corporation in Kerala without coastline?",
    "answerText": " Thrissur"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 88351,
    "questionText": " Which temple is known as ‘Dakshina Dwaraka’?",
    "answerText": " Guruvayur"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 88352,
    "questionText": " Silent Valley is in the district of?",
    "answerText": " Palakkad"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 88353,
    "questionText": " In which district is J.P. Smritivana is situated?",
    "answerText": " Palakkad"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 88354,
    "questionText": " Jainimedu, where Kumaranasan wrote ‘Veenapoovu’ is in the district of?",
    "answerText": " Palakkad"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 88355,
    "questionText": " The area where black soil is found in Kerala?",
    "answerText": " Chittur"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 88356,
    "questionText": " Ezhuthachan passed away at?",
    "answerText": " Chittur"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 88357,
    "questionText": " The district abundant in cotton soil?",
    "answerText": " Palakkad"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 88358,
    "questionText": " Karippur, where the Kozhikode air port is situated is in the district of?",
    "answerText": " Malappuram"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 88359,
    "questionText": " Venue of Mamankom was?",
    "answerText": " Thirunavaya"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 88360,
    "questionText": " The headquarters of naval force of Zamorin at the time of the arrival of Vasco da Gama was?",
    "answerText": " Ponnani"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 88361,
    "questionText": " Where is Thekkinkad ground, which is the venue of the famous Pooram festival?",
    "answerText": " Thrissur"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 88362,
    "questionText": " The capital of Kulasekharas was?",
    "answerText": " Mahodayapuram"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 88363,
    "questionText": " In which district is Chimminy Sanctuary?",
    "answerText": " Thrissur"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 88364,
    "questionText": " In which district is Punnayurkkulam?",
    "answerText": " Thrissur"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 88365,
    "questionText": " The Triprayar temple in Thrissur district is dedicated to?",
    "answerText": " Srirama"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 88366,
    "questionText": " The seat of Azhvanchery Tambrakkal is ...... near Thirunavaya?",
    "answerText": " Athavanad"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 88367,
    "questionText": " In which district is Kadampuzha temple?",
    "answerText": " Malappuram"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 88368,
    "questionText": " Thusharagiri is a tourish centre in the district of?",
    "answerText": " Kozhikode"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 88369,
    "questionText": " NH 212 connects Moolahalla and?",
    "answerText": " Kozhikode"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 88370,
    "questionText": " Muthanga wild life sanctuary is in the district of?",
    "answerText": " Wayanad"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 88371,
    "questionText": " The district in Kerala shares border with Tamil Nadu and Karnataka?",
    "answerText": " Wayanad"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 88372,
    "questionText": " The taluk in Kerala shares border with Tamil Nadu and Karnataka?",
    "answerText": " Sulthan Bathery"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 88373,
    "questionText": " Sweet Meet Street (SM Street) or Mitayitheruvu which is plot of “Oru Theruvinte Katha’ by SK Pottakkad is in the district of?",
    "answerText": " Kozhikode"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 88374,
    "questionText": " The second city Corporation in in Kerala?",
    "answerText": " Kozhikode"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 88375,
    "questionText": " Mananchira Ground is at?",
    "answerText": " Kozhikode"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 88376,
    "questionText": " Kappad, where Vasco da Gama landed on 20th May, 1498 is in the district of?",
    "answerText": " Kozhikode"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 88377,
    "questionText": " The museum at East Hill in Kozhikode is named after?",
    "answerText": " Pazhassi Raja"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 88378,
    "questionText": " The headquarters of Malabar district during the British regime?",
    "answerText": " Kozhikode"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 88379,
    "questionText": " The headquarters of areas of Malabar when it was under the control of Tipu Sultan?",
    "answerText": " Farokk"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 88380,
    "questionText": " The districts in Kerala without railway line are Idukky and?",
    "answerText": " Wayanad"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 88381,
    "questionText": " The districts that lead in the production of spices are Idukky and...... ?",
    "answerText": " Wayanad"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 88382,
    "questionText": " In which district is Sugandhagiri Project?",
    "answerText": " Wayanad"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 88383,
    "questionText": " The headquarters of Wayanad district?",
    "answerText": " Kalpetta"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 88384,
    "questionText": " In which district is Valliyurkavu?",
    "answerText": " Wayanad"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 88385,
    "questionText": " Kerala Folklore Academy is at?",
    "answerText": " Kannur"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 88386,
    "questionText": " In which district is Aralam santuary?",
    "answerText": " Kannur"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 88387,
    "questionText": " Andhakaranazhi connects ...... and Arabian sea?",
    "answerText": " Vembanad lake"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 88388,
    "questionText": " The port established by Raja Kesavadas, Dewan of Travancore?",
    "answerText": " Alappuzha"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 88389,
    "questionText": " In which district is Thanneermukkom Barrage?",
    "answerText": " Alappuzha"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 88390,
    "questionText": " In which district is Punnapra-Vayalar Memorial?",
    "answerText": " Alappuzha"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 88391,
    "questionText": " Thanneermukkam barrage is across ?",
    "answerText": " Vembanad lake"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 88392,
    "questionText": " NH-17 begins in Kerala at?",
    "answerText": " Edappally"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 88393,
    "questionText": " Oil Refinery in Kerala is situated at?",
    "answerText": " Ambalamugal"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 88394,
    "questionText": " Which European power built Bolghatty Palace?",
    "answerText": " Dutch"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 88395,
    "questionText": " The place in Kerala where rice is cultivated below sea level?",
    "answerText": " Kuttanad"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 88396,
    "questionText": " The district in Kerala with least reserve forest?",
    "answerText": " Alappuzha"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 88397,
    "questionText": " Which beach is the back ground of the novel ‘Chemmeen”?",
    "answerText": " Purakkad"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 88398,
    "questionText": " The headquarters of Idukky district?",
    "answerText": " Painav"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 88399,
    "questionText": " Power house of Idukky hydel project is situated at?",
    "answerText": " Moolamattom"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 88400,
    "questionText": " The village in Idukky district that was ceded to Ernakulam district, which shifted the Idukky district to the second rank in area?",
    "answerText": " Kuttampuzha"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 88401,
    "questionText": " The island formed after the flood of 1341?",
    "answerText": " Vypin"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 88402,
    "questionText": " INS Venduruthy is situated at?",
    "answerText": " Kochi"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 88403,
    "questionText": " In which district is Malayatoor, a holy place for Christians?",
    "answerText": " Ernakulam"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 88404,
    "questionText": " The Smart City Project is implemented at?",
    "answerText": " Kochi"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 88405,
    "questionText": " Which temple is related to ‘Makam Thozhal’?",
    "answerText": " Chottanikkara"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 88406,
    "questionText": " French occupied area in Kerala was?",
    "answerText": " Mahe"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 88407,
    "questionText": " In which district is Puralimala?",
    "answerText": " Kannur"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 88408,
    "questionText": " In which district is Parassinikadav Muthappan temple?",
    "answerText": " Kannur"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 88409,
    "questionText": " The place known as ‘Second Bardoli’?",
    "answerText": " Payyannur"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 88410,
    "questionText": " Which town is known as ‘Circus town in Kerala’?",
    "answerText": " Thalassery"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 88411,
    "questionText": " The fort in Kerala built by Sivappa Naik of Bidanur?",
    "answerText": " Bakel"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 88412,
    "questionText": " The pass that connects Kerala and Kudagu?",
    "answerText": " Perambady"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 88413,
    "questionText": " The place known as ‘the Cherrapunji of Kerala’?",
    "answerText": " Lakkidi"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 88414,
    "questionText": " Which European power built the Thalassery fort?",
    "answerText": " British"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 88415,
    "questionText": " The district of the Union Territory of Puducherry that shares border with Kerala?",
    "answerText": " Mahe"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 88416,
    "questionText": " Which place was the centre of activities of Herman Gundert?",
    "answerText": " Thalassery"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 88417,
    "questionText": " In which district is Mappila bay harbour?",
    "answerText": " Kannur"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 88418,
    "questionText": " The seat of Arakkal kingdom, the only Muslim dynasty in Kerala?",
    "answerText": " Kannur"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 88419,
    "questionText": " Which district in Kerala has the least number of Taluks?",
    "answerText": " Wayanad"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 88420,
    "questionText": " The northernmost back water in Kerala?",
    "answerText": " Uppala"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 88421,
    "questionText": " Which area was called ‘Martha’ by the foreigners?",
    "answerText": " Karunagappally"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 88422,
    "questionText": " The Palaruvi waterfalls is in the district of?",
    "answerText": " Kollam"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 88423,
    "questionText": " In which district the tourist spot Perumthenaruvi is situated?",
    "answerText": " Pathanamthitta"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 88424,
    "questionText": " In which district is Ramakkalmedu, the famous tourist centre?",
    "answerText": " Idukki"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 88425,
    "questionText": " Veli tourist village is in the district of?",
    "answerText": " Thiruvananthapuram"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 88426,
    "questionText": " The place famous for ‘Muniyaras’?",
    "answerText": " Marayur"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 88427,
    "questionText": " The place in Idukky district, famous for sandal forests?",
    "answerText": " Marayur"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 88428,
    "questionText": " The place in Kerala famous for ‘Neelakurinji’?",
    "answerText": " Munnar"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 88429,
    "questionText": " The place known as ‘Naura’ in ancient period?",
    "answerText": " Kannur"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 88430,
    "questionText": " The place where a garden was built in memory of the national leaders?",
    "answerText": " Peruvannamuzhi"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 88431,
    "questionText": " Where is ‘Joothakkulam’ in Kerala?",
    "answerText": " Madayi"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 88432,
    "questionText": " Where is Pazhassi Kudeeram situated?",
    "answerText": " Mananthavady"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 88433,
    "questionText": " Which area was once known as Chempakassery?",
    "answerText": " Ambalappuzha"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 88434,
    "questionText": " Which area was once known as Karappuram?",
    "answerText": " Cherthala"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 88435,
    "questionText": " Which sanctuary was formerly known as Nellikkampatty?",
    "answerText": " Thekkady"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 88436,
    "questionText": " Which river was known as ‘Baris’ in ancient times?",
    "answerText": " Pamba"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 88437,
    "questionText": " The region known as ‘Porainadu’ in Sangam age?",
    "answerText": " Palakkad"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 88438,
    "questionText": " Edakkal Caves are in the district of?",
    "answerText": " Wayanad"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 88439,
    "questionText": " In which century Kathakali was originated?",
    "answerText": " 17th"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 88440,
    "questionText": " In which district is Agasthyarkootam?",
    "answerText": " Thiruvananthapuram"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 88441,
    "questionText": " In which district is Athirappally- Vazhachal waterfalls?",
    "answerText": " Thrissur"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 88442,
    "questionText": " In which district is Kuruva island?",
    "answerText": " Wayanad"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 88443,
    "questionText": " In which district is Sankhumukham beach?",
    "answerText": " Thiruvananthapuram"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 88444,
    "questionText": " In which district is Thattekkad bird santuary?",
    "answerText": " Ernakulam"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 88445,
    "questionText": " In which lake is Pathiramanal island?",
    "answerText": " Vembanad"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 88446,
    "questionText": " In which place is Papanasam beach?",
    "answerText": " Varkala"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 88447,
    "questionText": " Payyoli beach is in the district of?",
    "answerText": " Kozhikode"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 88448,
    "questionText": " Pookkode lake is in the district of?",
    "answerText": " Wayanad"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 88449,
    "questionText": " Satvikam, Angikam, Vachikam and Aharyam are four types of?",
    "answerText": " Acting"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 88450,
    "questionText": " Subhadradhananjayam and Thapathisamvaranam were written by?",
    "answerText": " Kulasekharavarma"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 88451,
    "questionText": " Summer station of erstwhile princely state of Travancore, situated in Idukky district?",
    "answerText": " Peerumedu"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 88452,
    "questionText": " Swati Thirunal constructed ‘Kuthira Malika’ at?",
    "answerText": " Thiruvananthapuram"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 88453,
    "questionText": " Thankassery light house is in the district of?",
    "answerText": " Kollam"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 88454,
    "questionText": " The exponent of Kathakali?",
    "answerText": " Kottarakkara Thampuran"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 88455,
    "questionText": " The first person in Kerala to write Sanskrit Drama?",
    "answerText": " Saktibhadran"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 88456,
    "questionText": " The mudras of ‘Kathakali’ are adopted from?",
    "answerText": " Koodiyattam"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 88457,
    "questionText": " The place known as ‘little Mecca’?",
    "answerText": " Ponnani"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 88458,
    "questionText": " Where is ‘Joothakkunnu’ in Kerala?",
    "answerText": " Chavakkad"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 88459,
    "questionText": " Which art form is exclusively performed by the members of Chakyarkooth?",
    "answerText": " Koodiyattam"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 88460,
    "questionText": " Which palace is in Tamil Nadu but it is owned by the Government of Kerala?",
    "answerText": " Padmanabhapuram"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 88461,
    "questionText": " Who renovated the Krishnapuram palace?",
    "answerText": " Marthandavarma"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 88462,
    "questionText": " Primitive form of Kathakali?",
    "answerText": " Ramanattam"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 88463,
    "questionText": " The literary part of Kathakali?",
    "answerText": " Attakkatha"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 88464,
    "questionText": " A dance form evolved in Kerala under the patronage of Christian Church?",
    "answerText": " Chavittunatakam"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 88465,
    "questionText": " Ammannur Madhava Chakyar is related to?",
    "answerText": " Koodiyattom"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 88466,
    "questionText": " Chavittunatakam was evolved as an alternative to?",
    "answerText": " Kathakali"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 88467,
    "questionText": " In which district is Chakkulath Kavu?",
    "answerText": " Alappuzha"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 88468,
    "questionText": " In which district is Fantacy Park?",
    "answerText": " Palakkad"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 88469,
    "questionText": " In which district is Pathiramanal island?",
    "answerText": " Alappuzha"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 88470,
    "questionText": " In which district is Wagamon?",
    "answerText": " Idukki"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 88471,
    "questionText": " Mudiyettu is an art form related to ....... temples?",
    "answerText": " Bhadrakali"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 88472,
    "questionText": " St.Angelos fort in Kannur was built by the?",
    "answerText": " Portuguese"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 88473,
    "questionText": " The birth place of Chavittunatakam?",
    "answerText": " Matttancherry"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 88474,
    "questionText": " The Dutch Palace of Kochi was built by the?",
    "answerText": " Portuguese"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 88475,
    "questionText": " The fort built by Somasekhara Naik of Ikkeri dynasty?",
    "answerText": " Hosdurg"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 88476,
    "questionText": " The fort in Thiruvananthapuram district that was built by the British in 17th century?",
    "answerText": " Anchengo"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 88477,
    "questionText": " The most refined dance form of Kerala?",
    "answerText": " Kathakali"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 88478,
    "questionText": " The present form of Kathakali was designed by?",
    "answerText": " Kottayam Thampuran"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 88479,
    "questionText": " Which art form is performed by the members of Malayan and Mannan communities?",
    "answerText": " Theyyam"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 88480,
    "questionText": " Which traditional art form is related to Pulluvar?",
    "answerText": " Sarpam Thullal"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 88481,
    "questionText": " Which work is also known as ‘Ashtapadi’?",
    "answerText": " Gitagovinda"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 88482,
    "questionText": " Who authored ‘Prananathenenikku nalkiya paramananda rasathe’?",
    "answerText": " Irayimman Thampy"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 88483,
    "questionText": " Who designed the current form of dressing in Mohiniyattam?",
    "answerText": " Swati Trunal"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 88484,
    "questionText": " Charalkkunnu is a hill station in ...... district. ?",
    "answerText": " Pathanamthitta"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 88485,
    "questionText": " In which district is Kappil beach?",
    "answerText": " Kasargod"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 88486,
    "questionText": " In which district is Pakshipathalam?",
    "answerText": " Wayanad"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 88487,
    "questionText": " In which district is Payyambalam beach?",
    "answerText": " Kannur"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 88488,
    "questionText": " In which district Pookkode lake is situated?",
    "answerText": " Wayanad"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 88489,
    "questionText": " In which hills the famous Edakkal caves are situated?",
    "answerText": " Ambukuthimal"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 88490,
    "questionText": " In which place Jadayupara is situated?",
    "answerText": " Chadayamangalam"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 88491,
    "questionText": " The area known as Sairandrivanam in Mahabharat?",
    "answerText": " Silent Valley"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 88492,
    "questionText": " The famous marine drive in Kerala is at?",
    "answerText": " Ernakulam"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 88493,
    "questionText": " The national park which is famous lion tailed macaque?",
    "answerText": " Silent Valley"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 88494,
    "questionText": " Who is regarded as the father of Yakshagana?",
    "answerText": " Parthy Subban"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 88495,
    "questionText": " Who wrote the song’ Omanathinkal Kidavo’?",
    "answerText": " Irayimman Thampy"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 88496,
    "questionText": " In which century Thacholi Othernan lived?",
    "answerText": " 16th"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 88497,
    "questionText": " “Thekkan style’ in Kathakali was expounded by?",
    "answerText": " Kaplingattu Namboothiri"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 88498,
    "questionText": " A film directed by Priyadarshan that depicts a story in the back ground of freedom struggle of India?",
    "answerText": " Kalapani"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 88499,
    "questionText": " Gajendramoksham can be seen at the palace of?",
    "answerText": " Krishnapuram"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 88500,
    "questionText": " In which district is ‘Arjuna Nritham’ is a famous dance form?",
    "answerText": " Kottayam"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 88501,
    "questionText": " Oppana is a dance form performed by the women of ...... community?",
    "answerText": " Muslim"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 88502,
    "questionText": " Padayani is a dance form popular in the district of?",
    "answerText": " Pathanamthitta"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 88503,
    "questionText": " The famous ‘Ezharapponnana’ of Ettumanoor temple is made up of?",
    "answerText": " Wood"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 88504,
    "questionText": " The film based on the theme of ‘Count of Monte Christo’ by Alexander Dumas?",
    "answerText": " Padayottam"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 88505,
    "questionText": " The film based on the theme of ‘Othallo’ of Shakespeare?",
    "answerText": " Kaliyattam"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 88506,
    "questionText": " The first Dolby sterio film in Malayalam?",
    "answerText": " Kalapani"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 88507,
    "questionText": " The first film directed by M T Vasudevan Nair?",
    "answerText": " Nirmalyam"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 88508,
    "questionText": " The first Malayalam film to get Golden Camera award in Cannes film festival?",
    "answerText": " Maranasimhasanam"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 88509,
    "questionText": " The first state in India to start the cultivation of Rubber?",
    "answerText": " Kerala"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 88510,
    "questionText": " The headquarters of Kerala Agricultural University?",
    "answerText": " Mannuthy"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 88511,
    "questionText": " The largest strike organised by the Communist party in Kerala?",
    "answerText": " Punnapra-Vayalar"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 88512,
    "questionText": " The Malayalam film in which Latha Mangeshkar was a playback singer?",
    "answerText": " Nellu"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 88513,
    "questionText": " The Malayalam film in which no woman was acted?",
    "answerText": " Mathilukal"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 88514,
    "questionText": " The poet who revived Kathakali?",
    "answerText": " Vallathol"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 88515,
    "questionText": " Which crop is known as ‘the gold of the wasteland’?",
    "answerText": " Cashew"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 88516,
    "questionText": " The first film in Malayalam was made based on a literary work?",
    "answerText": " Marthandavarma"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 88517,
    "questionText": " The first Malayalam film that was nominated for Oscar?",
    "answerText": " Guru"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 88518,
    "questionText": " The first Malayalam film to get President’s silver medal?",
    "answerText": " Neelakkuyil"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 88519,
    "questionText": " The first film society in Kerala?",
    "answerText": " Chitralekha"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 88520,
    "questionText": " The first film to get the award of Govt. of Kerala for best film?",
    "answerText": " Kumarasambhavam"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 88521,
    "questionText": " Which district has the least area under paddy cultivation?",
    "answerText": " Idukki"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 88522,
    "questionText": " Which district in Kerala has the largest area under paddy cultivation?",
    "answerText": " Palakkad"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 88523,
    "questionText": " Which vesha is usually used for female charecters in Kathakali?",
    "answerText": " Minukku"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 88524,
    "questionText": " The king of Travancore who encouraged Tapioca cultivation?",
    "answerText": " Visakham Tirunal"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 88525,
    "questionText": " The largest mural painting in Kerala?",
    "answerText": " Gajendramoksham"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 88526,
    "questionText": " The mural painting ‘Aghoramoorthy’ can be seen at the temple of?",
    "answerText": " Ettumanoor"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 88527,
    "questionText": " The year of split in Communist Party?",
    "answerText": 1964
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 88528,
    "questionText": " The youngest Malayalam actress to get national award for best actress?",
    "answerText": " Monisha"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 88529,
    "questionText": " What is called the ‘king of spices’?",
    "answerText": " Pepper"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 88530,
    "questionText": " What is known as ‘queen of spices’?",
    "answerText": " Cardomom"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 88531,
    "questionText": " What is known as the ‘grains of paradise’?",
    "answerText": " Cardomom"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 88532,
    "questionText": " Who led Communist Party of India(Marxist) in Kerala after the split?",
    "answerText": " EMS"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 88533,
    "questionText": " The first rubber park in Kerala?",
    "answerText": " Airapuram"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 88534,
    "questionText": " Which is the cash crop cultivated in the largest area in Kerala?",
    "answerText": " Rubber"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 88535,
    "questionText": " Gandhiji visited Kerala for the first time in?",
    "answerText": 1920
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 88536,
    "questionText": " Gandhiji visited Kerala for the last time in?",
    "answerText": 1937
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 88537,
    "questionText": " In which year ‘Abstention movement’ was started in Travancore?",
    "answerText": 1932
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 88538,
    "questionText": " Karivellur strike was in?",
    "answerText": 1946
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 88539,
    "questionText": " Kayyur strike was in?",
    "answerText": 1941
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 88540,
    "questionText": " Name the newspaper launched in 1942 at Kozhikode as the mouthpiece of Communist party in Kerala?",
    "answerText": " Desabhimani"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 88541,
    "questionText": " The prohibition on the Communist party was withdrawn in?",
    "answerText": 1942
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 88542,
    "questionText": " The publication of ‘Desabhimani’, the mouth piece of Communist was started in 1942 from?",
    "answerText": " Kozhikode"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 88543,
    "questionText": " Under whose leadeship Kochi Rajya Prajamandalam was formed in 1941?",
    "answerText": " VR Krishanezhuthachan"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 88544,
    "questionText": " The district which is the largest producer of Coffee in Kerala?",
    "answerText": " Wayanad"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 88545,
    "questionText": " The district which is the largest producer of Rubber in Kerala?",
    "answerText": " Kottayam"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 88546,
    "questionText": " The district which is the largest producer of Tea in Kerala?",
    "answerText": " Idukki"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 88547,
    "questionText": " The film by Shaji N.Karun based on the theme of the controversial Rajan Case?",
    "answerText": " Piravi"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 88548,
    "questionText": " The film ‘Neythukaran’ depicts the life of?",
    "answerText": " EMS"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 88549,
    "questionText": " The first digital film in Malayalam?",
    "answerText": " Moonnamathoral"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 88550,
    "questionText": " The first sponsored film in Malayalam?",
    "answerText": " Makalkku"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 88551,
    "questionText": " Who was known as Kerala Marx?",
    "answerText": " K Damodaran"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 88552,
    "questionText": " In which date EMS ministry was dismissed?",
    "answerText": " 31st July;1959"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 88553,
    "questionText": " In which date the first ministry came into power?",
    "answerText": " 5th April; 1957"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 88554,
    "questionText": " In which district is Attappady tribal settlement?",
    "answerText": " Palakkad"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 88555,
    "questionText": " In which district is Parassinikadavu snake park?",
    "answerText": " Kannur"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 88556,
    "questionText": " India’s first gymnastic training centre was established in?",
    "answerText": " Thalassery"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 88557,
    "questionText": " The smallest river in Kerala?",
    "answerText": " Mancheswaram"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 88558,
    "questionText": " The southernmost river in India?",
    "answerText": " Neyyar"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 88559,
    "questionText": " ‘The Vrindavan of Kerala’?",
    "answerText": " Malampuzha Garden"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 88560,
    "questionText": " The year of Wagon Tragedy?",
    "answerText": 1921
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 88561,
    "questionText": " ‘TheNetherlands of Kerala’?",
    "answerText": " Kuttanad"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 88562,
    "questionText": " What is known as ‘Kerala Kumbhamela’?",
    "answerText": " Makaravilakk"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 88563,
    "questionText": " The first south Indian film to get president’s gold medal?",
    "answerText": " Chemmeen"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 88564,
    "questionText": " The first step in the performance of Kathakali?",
    "answerText": " Kelikottu"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 88565,
    "questionText": " The most beautiful ‘Vesha’ in Kathakali?",
    "answerText": " Pacha"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 88566,
    "questionText": " The first Bachat district in Kerala?",
    "answerText": " Ernakulam"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 88567,
    "questionText": " The first church built by the Europeans in India is.......... at Kochi. ?",
    "answerText": " St. Francis Church"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 88568,
    "questionText": " The first fort built by Europeans in India?",
    "answerText": " Pallippuram"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 88569,
    "questionText": " The first teak museum in India?",
    "answerText": " Nilambur"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 88570,
    "questionText": " The industrial capital of Kerala?",
    "answerText": " Kochi"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 88571,
    "questionText": " The northernmost river in India?",
    "answerText": " Mancheswaram river"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 88572,
    "questionText": " The number of mudras in Kathakali?",
    "answerText": 24
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 88573,
    "questionText": " The number of types of musical instruments used in Panchavadyam?",
    "answerText": 6
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 88574,
    "questionText": " The role immortalised by Mammooty in the film ‘Oru Vadakkan Veeragatha’?",
    "answerText": " Chanthu"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 88575,
    "questionText": " Thiruvathirakkali is also known as?",
    "answerText": " Kaikottikkali"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 88576,
    "questionText": " Who discovered the Edakkal caves?",
    "answerText": " Fasset"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 88577,
    "questionText": " ‘Mundakan’ is a term related to?",
    "answerText": " Paddy"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 88578,
    "questionText": " Punnapra-Vayalar agitation was in?",
    "answerText": 1946
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 88579,
    "questionText": " The Dewan of Travancore who suppressed Punnapra-Vayalar agitation?",
    "answerText": " CP Ramaswamy Iyer"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 88580,
    "questionText": " The exponent of Ottan Thullal?",
    "answerText": " Kunchan Nambiar"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 88581,
    "questionText": " The film based on the theme of Kayyur strike?",
    "answerText": " Meenamasathile Sooryan"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 88582,
    "questionText": " The film based on the theme of Malabar Revolt?",
    "answerText": 1921
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 88583,
    "questionText": " The film ‘Guru’ depicts the life of?",
    "answerText": " Karunakara Guru"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 88584,
    "questionText": " Which is known as ‘gate way of Wayanad’?",
    "answerText": " Lakkidi"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 88585,
    "questionText": " Which is known as ‘land of latex’ (land of Rubber)?",
    "answerText": " Kottayam"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 88586,
    "questionText": " Which place is known as ‘poorman’s Ooty’?",
    "answerText": " Nelliampathy"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 88587,
    "questionText": " Which river is also known by the name ‘Beppurppuzha’?",
    "answerText": " Chaliyar"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 88588,
    "questionText": " Which river was called “the English channel in India’ as it separated the British and French occupied territories?",
    "answerText": " Mayyazhi river"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 88589,
    "questionText": " Who headed the first ministry in Kerala?",
    "answerText": " EMS Namboothirippad"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 88590,
    "questionText": " Who was the first secretary of the Kerala Pradesh Congress Committee formed in 1920?",
    "answerText": " K Madhavan Nair"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 88591,
    "questionText": " Who was the only member in the first EMS ministry who had previous experience as minister?",
    "answerText": " Dr AR Menon"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 88592,
    "questionText": " Who was the first Food minister of Kerala?",
    "answerText": " KC George"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 88593,
    "questionText": " The river which is known as ‘Dakshina Bhagirathi’?",
    "answerText": " Pamba"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 88594,
    "questionText": " In which district is Malampuzha dam?",
    "answerText": " Palakkad"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 88595,
    "questionText": " In which district is Moozhiyar dam and Kakki dam?",
    "answerText": " Pathanamthitta"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 88596,
    "questionText": " In which district is Patrakkadavu project?",
    "answerText": " Palakkad"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 88597,
    "questionText": " In which district, Sasthamkotta the largest fresh water lake in Kerala is situated?",
    "answerText": " Kollam"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 88598,
    "questionText": " In which river Chenkulam hydel project is built?",
    "answerText": " Muthirappuzh"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 88599,
    "questionText": " In which river is Athirappally waterfalls?",
    "answerText": " Chalakkudy"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 88600,
    "questionText": " In which river the Dharmadom island is situated?",
    "answerText": " Anchrakkandy"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 88601,
    "questionText": " In which river the largest number of power projects are established?",
    "answerText": " Periyar"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 88602,
    "questionText": " introduced Land Reforms Bill in Kerala legislative assembly ?",
    "answerText": " KR Gowri"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 88603,
    "questionText": " Kalady and Aluva are on the banks of?",
    "answerText": " Periyar"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 88604,
    "questionText": " Kalpathy Shiva temple famous for car festival is in the district of?",
    "answerText": " Palakkad"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 88605,
    "questionText": " Mamankom was held on the banks of the river?",
    "answerText": " Bharatappuzha"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 88606,
    "questionText": " The dam which is constructed with assistance of Canada?",
    "answerText": " Idukki dam"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 88607,
    "questionText": " The district in which the highest peak in Kerala is situated?",
    "answerText": " Idukki"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 88608,
    "questionText": " The number of rivers in Kerala?",
    "answerText": 44
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 88609,
    "questionText": " The place which is the venue of the largest Hindu religious conference in Kerala?",
    "answerText": " Cherukolppuzha"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 88610,
    "questionText": " The river flows through silent valley?",
    "answerText": " Kunthippuzha"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 88611,
    "questionText": " The river related to Pathrakkadavu project?",
    "answerText": " Kunthippuzha"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 88612,
    "questionText": " The river which originates from Pulichimala?",
    "answerText": " Pamba"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 88613,
    "questionText": " The second largest sanctuary in Kerala?",
    "answerText": " Wayanad"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 88614,
    "questionText": " The second longest river in Kerala?",
    "answerText": " Bharatappuzha"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 88615,
    "questionText": " The temple of Kerala without compound wall?",
    "answerText": " Ochira"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 88616,
    "questionText": " Thirunavaya is on the banks of?",
    "answerText": " Bharatappuzha"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 88617,
    "questionText": " To which temple ‘Chitra Pournami’ festival is related?",
    "answerText": " Mangaladevi"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 88618,
    "questionText": " Where is Hill Palace Museum, the largest archaeological museum in Kerala situated?",
    "answerText": " Tripunithura"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 88619,
    "questionText": " Which district has the largest number of block panchayats?",
    "answerText": " Thrissur"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 88620,
    "questionText": " Which river has two branches namely Mangalappuzha and Marthandanppuzha?",
    "answerText": " Periyar"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 88621,
    "questionText": " Which river is also known as Ponnanippuzha?",
    "answerText": " Bharatappuzha"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 88622,
    "questionText": " Muthirappuzha is a tributary of?",
    "answerText": " Periyar"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 88623,
    "questionText": " ‘Panthrandu Vilakk’ is the festival of?",
    "answerText": " Oachira"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 88624,
    "questionText": " Periyar rises from?",
    "answerText": " Sivagiri hills"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 88625,
    "questionText": " The annual festival of which temple is known as ‘Bharani’?",
    "answerText": " Kodungallur"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 88626,
    "questionText": " The annual festival of which temple is known as ‘Ekadasi’?",
    "answerText": " Guruvayur"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 88627,
    "questionText": " The city of Kasargod is near to the river of?",
    "answerText": " Chandragiri"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 88628,
    "questionText": " Which river was known as ‘Choorni’ in ancient times?",
    "answerText": " Periyar"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 88629,
    "questionText": " Who introduced Education Bill in Kerala legislative assembly ?",
    "answerText": " Joseph Mundassery"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 88630,
    "questionText": " Who was in charge of Home department in the end of the first EMS ministry?",
    "answerText": " C Achuthamenon"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 88631,
    "questionText": " In which district is Mullaperiyar dam?",
    "answerText": " Idukki"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 88632,
    "questionText": " In which district of Pazhassi dam?",
    "answerText": " Kannur"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 88633,
    "questionText": " In which river is Banasurasagar Dam?",
    "answerText": " Kabani"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 88634,
    "questionText": " In which river is Peppara Dam?",
    "answerText": " Karamana"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 88635,
    "questionText": " In which river is Sabarigiri Project?",
    "answerText": " Pamba"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 88636,
    "questionText": " Kallada, the largest irrigation project is in the district of?",
    "answerText": " Kollam"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 88637,
    "questionText": " Kuruva island is in the river?",
    "answerText": " Kabani"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 88638,
    "questionText": " Navamukunda Temple is situated in the district of?",
    "answerText": " Malappuram"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 88639,
    "questionText": " ‘Ormayude Arakal’ is the autobiography of?",
    "answerText": " Vaikom Muhammad Basheer"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 88640,
    "questionText": " Ponmudi Dam is in the river?",
    "answerText": " Periyar"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 88641,
    "questionText": " Sabarimala temple is in the district of?",
    "answerText": " Pathanamthitta"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 88642,
    "questionText": " The dam situated between Kuravan and Kurathi hills?",
    "answerText": " Idukki"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 88643,
    "questionText": " The disrtict with the longest coastline?",
    "answerText": " Kannur"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 88644,
    "questionText": " The district in Kerala which has the largest number of villages?",
    "answerText": " Palakkad"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 88645,
    "questionText": " The district with the largest number of rivers flowing?",
    "answerText": " Kasargod"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 88646,
    "questionText": " The festival ‘Ashtami’ is related to the temple of?",
    "answerText": " Vaikom"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 88647,
    "questionText": " The festival of ......... temple is known as ‘Aarat’?",
    "answerText": " Padamabhaswamy Temple"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 88648,
    "questionText": " The first education minister of minister?",
    "answerText": " Joseph Mundassery"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 88649,
    "questionText": " The first electricity minister of Kerala?",
    "answerText": " VR Krishna Iyer"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 88650,
    "questionText": " The first hydro electric project in Kerala was constructed in the river?",
    "answerText": " Muthirappuzha"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 88651,
    "questionText": " The first revenue minister of Kerala?",
    "answerText": " KR Gowri"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 88652,
    "questionText": " The headquarters of Deepika, the oldest news paper in Kerala?",
    "answerText": " Kottayam"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 88653,
    "questionText": " The hottest place in Kerala?",
    "answerText": " Punalur"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 88654,
    "questionText": " The largest hydel project in Kerala?",
    "answerText": " Idukki"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 88655,
    "questionText": " The largest jail in Kerala?",
    "answerText": " Thiruvananthapuram"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 88656,
    "questionText": " The longest river in Kerala?",
    "answerText": " Periyar"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 88657,
    "questionText": " The number of east flowing rivers in Kerala?",
    "answerText": 3
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 88658,
    "questionText": " The largest dam in Kerala , Malampuzha dam, is in the district of?",
    "answerText": " Palakkad"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 88659,
    "questionText": " The largest earthern dam in Kerala?",
    "answerText": " Banasurasagar"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 88660,
    "questionText": " The largest rain forest in Kerala?",
    "answerText": " Silent valley"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 88661,
    "questionText": " The largest underground power station in Kerala?",
    "answerText": " Moolamattom"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 88662,
    "questionText": " The longest boat race in Kerala?",
    "answerText": " Payippat"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 88663,
    "questionText": " The oldest synagogue in Commonweath nations is situated at?",
    "answerText": " Kochi"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 88664,
    "questionText": " The place in Kerala famous for Nagaraja Temple?",
    "answerText": " Mannarassala"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 88665,
    "questionText": " The place in Thiruvananthapuram district where Parasurama temple is situated?",
    "answerText": " Thiruvallam"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 88666,
    "questionText": " The ritual ‘Murajapam’ is associated to the temple of?",
    "answerText": " Padmanabhaswamy Temple"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 88667,
    "questionText": " The taluk in Kerala with the longest coastline?",
    "answerText": " Cherthala"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 88668,
    "questionText": " Which district in Kerala has the largest number of Grama Panchayats?",
    "answerText": " Malappuram"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 88669,
    "questionText": " Which district in kerala has the largest number of Panchayat Raj Institutions?",
    "answerText": " Malappuram"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 88670,
    "questionText": " Which district in Kerala has the largest number of Taluks?",
    "answerText": " Ernakulam"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 88671,
    "questionText": " A sun temple is sitated at Adithyapuram in ........ District?",
    "answerText": " Kottayam"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 88672,
    "questionText": " Thiruvelli temple is dedicated to?",
    "answerText": " Vishnu"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 88673,
    "questionText": " ‘Arangu Kanatha Nadan’ is the autobiography of?",
    "answerText": " Thikkodian"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 88674,
    "questionText": " Asia’s tallest church (Basilica of Our Lady of Dolours) is situated at?",
    "answerText": " Thrissur"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 88675,
    "questionText": " Idamalayar Dam is in the river?",
    "answerText": " Periyar"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 88676,
    "questionText": " In which river is Anayirankal Dam?",
    "answerText": " Periyar"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 88677,
    "questionText": " The district in Kerala with the lowest rainfall?",
    "answerText": " Palakkad"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 88678,
    "questionText": " The district with the largest number of Jews in Kerala?",
    "answerText": " Ernakulam"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 88679,
    "questionText": " The ‘Ezharapponnana’ of Ettumanoor temple is made up of?",
    "answerText": " Wood"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 88680,
    "questionText": " The highest town in Kerala?",
    "answerText": " Munnar"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 88681,
    "questionText": " Thoonakkadav Dam is in the river?",
    "answerText": " Chalakkudy"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 88682,
    "questionText": " Vadakkumnatha Temple is at?",
    "answerText": " Thrissur"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 88683,
    "questionText": " ‘Viplavasmaranakal’ is the autobiography of?",
    "answerText": " Puthuppally Raghavan"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 88684,
    "questionText": " ‘Athmakatha’ is the autobiography of?",
    "answerText": " EMS"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 88685,
    "questionText": " ‘Ethirpp’ is the autobiography of?",
    "answerText": " Kesavadev"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 88686,
    "questionText": " In which district is Arakkal Kettu?",
    "answerText": " Kannur"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 88687,
    "questionText": " In which district is Chirakkal Kovilakam?",
    "answerText": " Kannur"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 88688,
    "questionText": " In which district is Mayippadi Palace?",
    "answerText": " Kazargod"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 88689,
    "questionText": " In which river is Thenmala Dam?",
    "answerText": " Kallada"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 88690,
    "questionText": " In which river system is Mattuppetty Dam?",
    "answerText": " Periyar"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 88691,
    "questionText": " In which river system is Meenkara Dam?",
    "answerText": " Bharatappuzha"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 88692,
    "questionText": " In which river system is Neryamangalam Dam?",
    "answerText": " Periyar"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 88693,
    "questionText": " ‘Kaviyude Kalpadukal’ is the autobiography of?",
    "answerText": " P Kunhiraman Nair"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 88694,
    "questionText": " ‘Njan’ is the autobiography of?",
    "answerText": " NN Pillai"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 88695,
    "questionText": " ‘Ormayude Olangalil’ is the autobiography of?",
    "answerText": " G Sankarakkurup"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 88696,
    "questionText": " Padmanabhapuram Palace is owned by Government of Kerala is in the district of?",
    "answerText": " Kanyakumari"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 88697,
    "questionText": " Parambikkulam Dam is in the river?",
    "answerText": " Chalakkudy"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 88698,
    "questionText": " ‘Service Story’ is the autobiography of?",
    "answerText": " Malayattoor"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 88699,
    "questionText": " Sholayar Dam is in the river?",
    "answerText": " Chalakkudy"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 88700,
    "questionText": " The Bolghatty Palace was built in?",
    "answerText": 1744
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 88701,
    "questionText": " The British Resident to Travancore, who stipulated some criteria for the appointments in Govt Service?",
    "answerText": " Colonel Monroe"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 88702,
    "questionText": " The king of Travancore when Malayali Memorial and Ezhava Memorial was submitted?",
    "answerText": " Sri Mulam Tirunal"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 88703,
    "questionText": " The King of Travancore when the first Public Service Commissioner was appointed?",
    "answerText": " Sri Chithira Tirunal"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 88704,
    "questionText": " The king who renovated Krishnapuram Palace?",
    "answerText": " Marthanda Varma"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 88705,
    "questionText": " In which river system is Chenkulam Dam?",
    "answerText": " Periyar"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 88706,
    "questionText": " In which river system is Cheruthoni Dam?",
    "answerText": " Periyar"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 88707,
    "questionText": " Who was the first chairman of the Thiru-Kochi Public Service Commission?",
    "answerText": " C.Kunhiraman"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 88708,
    "questionText": " Travancore bought Fort Manuel from the Dutch in?",
    "answerText": 1789
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 88709,
    "questionText": " The Ministry of EMS was the first to be dismissed under Article 356 of the constitution .It was in?",
    "answerText": 1959
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 88710,
    "questionText": " In which year Thiru -Kochi Public Service Commission was formed?",
    "answerText": 1949
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 88711,
    "questionText": " President’s rule was imposed in Thiru Kochi in?",
    "answerText": 1956
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 88712,
    "questionText": " The agitation that led to President’s rule in Kerala in 1959?",
    "answerText": " Liberation Struggle"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 88713,
    "questionText": " The king of Travancore who constructed Nedumkotta?",
    "answerText": " Dharma Raja"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 88714,
    "questionText": " The king of Travancore who constructed the Udayagiri Fort and Vattakottai(Circular Fort)which is now in Kanyakumari district?",
    "answerText": " MarthandaVarma"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 88715,
    "questionText": " In which river system is Kakki Dam?",
    "answerText": " Pamba"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 88716,
    "questionText": " In which river system is Kundala Dam?",
    "answerText": " Periyar"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 88717,
    "questionText": " Which district in Kerala has the largest number of cashew factories?",
    "answerText": " Kollam"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 88718,
    "questionText": " Which district is the largest producer of coffee in Kerala?",
    "answerText": " Wayanad"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 88719,
    "questionText": " Which district is the largest producer of tobacco in Kerala?",
    "answerText": " Kasargod"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 88720,
    "questionText": " Which temple is situated in a river island?",
    "answerText": " Chamravattom"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 88721,
    "questionText": " Who wrote “Kazhinja Kaalam’?",
    "answerText": " KP Kesavamenon"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 88722,
    "questionText": " ‘Smrithidarppanam ‘ is the autobiography of?",
    "answerText": " MP Manmadhan"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 88723,
    "questionText": " ‘Manasasmarami’ is the autobiography of?",
    "answerText": " S Guptan Nair"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 88724,
    "questionText": " “Athmakathakk Oru Amukham’ is the autobiography of?",
    "answerText": " Lalithambika Antharjanam"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 88725,
    "questionText": " In which river system is Pothundi Dam?",
    "answerText": " Bharatappuzha"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 88726,
    "questionText": " In which river system is Valayar Dam?",
    "answerText": " Bharatappuzha"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 88727,
    "questionText": " Janardhana Swamy Temple is situated at?",
    "answerText": " Varkala"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 88728,
    "questionText": " ‘Jeevitha Samaram’ is the autobiography of?",
    "answerText": " C Kesavan"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 88729,
    "questionText": " Kakkad Dam is in the river?",
    "answerText": " Pamba"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 88730,
    "questionText": " Koodalmanikya Temple at Iringalakkuda is dedicated to?",
    "answerText": " Bharata"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 88731,
    "questionText": " ‘Kozhinja Ilakal’ is the autobiography of?",
    "answerText": " Joseph Mundassery"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 88732,
    "questionText": " Kuthunkal, the largest private hydro electric project in Kerala is in the district of?",
    "answerText": " Idukki"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 88733,
    "questionText": " Malampuzha Dam is in the river system?",
    "answerText": " Bharatappuzha"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 88734,
    "questionText": " ‘Olivile Ormakal’ is the autobiography of?",
    "answerText": " Thoppil Bhasi"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 88735,
    "questionText": " Parabrahma Temple is at?",
    "answerText": " Ochira"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 88736,
    "questionText": " Peringalkuthu Dam is in the river?",
    "answerText": " Chalakkudy"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 88737,
    "questionText": " Anamudi, the highest peak in Kerala is in the panchayat of?",
    "answerText": " Munnar"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 88738,
    "questionText": " Arippa bird sanctuary is in which district?",
    "answerText": " Thiruvananthapuram"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 88739,
    "questionText": " Asramam tourist village is situated near the lake?",
    "answerText": " Ashatamudi"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 88740,
    "questionText": " At which place the Periyer divides into twoManglappuzha and Marthandanpuzha?",
    "answerText": " Aluva"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 88741,
    "questionText": " Ayyankali established ‘Sadhujana Paripalana Yogam’ in?",
    "answerText": 1907
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 88742,
    "questionText": " Chambakkulam boat race is held in ......?",
    "answerText": " Pamba river"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 88743,
    "questionText": " Chandanakavu where Melpathur memorial is situ ated is in the district of?",
    "answerText": " Malappuram"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 88744,
    "questionText": " Cherukolppuzha Hindu conference held on the banks of?",
    "answerText": " Pamba"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 88745,
    "questionText": " Communist League was founded in Thiruvananthapuram in?",
    "answerText": 1931
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 88746,
    "questionText": " Erumeli famous for religious harmony is in the district of?",
    "answerText": " Kottayam"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 88747,
    "questionText": " Farrokk in Kozhikode is famous for ....... industry?",
    "answerText": " Tile"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 88748,
    "questionText": " First minister in charge of Public Works?",
    "answerText": " TA Majeed"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 88749,
    "questionText": " Gavi is a tourist place in the distict of?",
    "answerText": " Pathanamthitta"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 88750,
    "questionText": " In ancient period Kottakkal in Malappuram district was known as?",
    "answerText": " Venkatakota"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 88751,
    "questionText": " In which district is Banasurasagar Dam?",
    "answerText": " Wayanad"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 88752,
    "questionText": " In which district is Idamalayar hydel project?",
    "answerText": " Ernakulam"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 88753,
    "questionText": " In which district is Iravikulam national park?",
    "answerText": " Idukki"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 88754,
    "questionText": " In which district is Kallil Bhagavati Temple, which was formerly a Jaina temple?",
    "answerText": " Ernakulam"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 88755,
    "questionText": " In which district is Lokanarkav situated?",
    "answerText": " Kozhikode"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 88756,
    "questionText": " In which district is Mangaladevi Temple?",
    "answerText": " Idukki"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 88757,
    "questionText": " In which district is Muzhuppilangad, the longest beach in Kerala?",
    "answerText": " Kannur"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 88758,
    "questionText": " In which district is Nallalam Thermal Project?",
    "answerText": " Kozhikode"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 88759,
    "questionText": " In which district Tulu language is spoken?",
    "answerText": " Kasargod"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 88760,
    "questionText": " In which distrrict the famous Malayalam poet Ulloor S.Parameswarayyar was born?",
    "answerText": " Kottayam"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 88761,
    "questionText": " In which river is Aruvikkara Dam?",
    "answerText": " Karamanayar"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 88762,
    "questionText": " In which river is Peruvannamuzhi Dam?",
    "answerText": " Kuttiadi"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 88763,
    "questionText": " In which river is Vazhani Dam?",
    "answerText": " Kecherippuzha"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 88764,
    "questionText": " In which river system is Bhuthathan Kettu Dam?",
    "answerText": " Periyar"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 88765,
    "questionText": " Karappuzha is the first hydro electric project is in the district of?",
    "answerText": " Wayanad"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 88766,
    "questionText": " Kasargod district was formed after the bifurcation of?",
    "answerText": " Kannur"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 88767,
    "questionText": " Killikurissimangalam, the birth place of Kunchan Nambiar is in the district of?",
    "answerText": " Palakkad"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 88768,
    "questionText": " Kizhattur, a place near Perinthalmanna is the birth place of?",
    "answerText": " Poonthanam"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 88769,
    "questionText": " KP Gopalan was in charge of the portfolio of?",
    "answerText": " Industry"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 88770,
    "questionText": " Land of Pooram?",
    "answerText": " Thrissur"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 88771,
    "questionText": " Land of Theyyam?",
    "answerText": " Kannur"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 88772,
    "questionText": " ‘Madabhoomi’ is the old name of?",
    "answerText": " Kochi"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 88773,
    "questionText": " Merryland, the second film studio in Kerala is situated at....... in Thiruvananthapuram district?",
    "answerText": " Nemom"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 88774,
    "questionText": " Muziris is the old name of?",
    "answerText": " Kodungallur"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 88775,
    "questionText": " Number of members in the first ministry of Kerala including Chief Minister?",
    "answerText": 11
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 88776,
    "questionText": " Old name of Angadippuram?",
    "answerText": " Valluvanagaram"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 88777,
    "questionText": " Old name of Kottackal?",
    "answerText": " Venkatakota"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 88778,
    "questionText": " Parayan and Seethnkan are forms of?",
    "answerText": " Ottan Thullal Indo-Norwegean Fisheries Community Project is situated at?"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 88779,
    "questionText": " Raja Ravi Varma, the first painter in Kerala to acquire international fame, passed away in?",
    "answerText": 1906
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 88780,
    "questionText": " The back ground of the novel, ‘God of Small Things’ by Arundathy Roy?",
    "answerText": " Aymanam"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 88781,
    "questionText": " The birth place of P.Kunjiraman Nair, the famous poet of Kerala?",
    "answerText": " Kanhangad"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 88782,
    "questionText": " The birth place of Rama Panicker, one of the Kannassa poets?",
    "answerText": " Niranam"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 88783,
    "questionText": " The birth place of Thacholi Othenan?",
    "answerText": " Vadakara"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 88784,
    "questionText": " The capital of the Aay dynasty was....... in Thiruvananthapuram district?",
    "answerText": " Vizhinjam"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 88785,
    "questionText": " The Chala market founded by Raja Kesavadas is in?",
    "answerText": " Thiruvananthapuram"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 88786,
    "questionText": " The Communist Party in Kerala formed in 1937 and functioned secretly. The decition to function openly was taken in a meeting held at ......... in 1939?",
    "answerText": " Pinarayi"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 88787,
    "questionText": " The Crocodile farm in Thiruvananthapuram district is at?",
    "answerText": " Neyyar Dam"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 88788,
    "questionText": " The district in Kerala where ‘Yakshagana’ is popular?",
    "answerText": " Kazargod"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 88789,
    "questionText": " The district in Kerala with the largest number of industrial establishments?",
    "answerText": " Ernakulam"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 88790,
    "questionText": " The district of Kerala with rich deposits of iron?",
    "answerText": " Kozhikode"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 88791,
    "questionText": " The district of Kerala with the largest number of Hindus?",
    "answerText": " Thiruvananthapuram"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 88792,
    "questionText": " The district that is known as the ‘rice bowl of Kerala’?",
    "answerText": " Palakkad"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 88793,
    "questionText": " The district where the largest number of regional languages are spoken?",
    "answerText": " Kasargod"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 88794,
    "questionText": " The district which is the largest producer of Cardomom in Kerala?",
    "answerText": " Idukki"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 88795,
    "questionText": " The district which is the largest producer of Tapioca?",
    "answerText": " Thiruvananthapuram"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 88796,
    "questionText": " The district with the largest number of Jains?",
    "answerText": " Wayanad"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 88797,
    "questionText": " The fort of Kunhali was buitlt at?",
    "answerText": " Puthupatanam"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 88798,
    "questionText": " The founder secretary of Communist Party in Kerala?",
    "answerText": " P Krishna Pillai"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 88799,
    "questionText": " The hottest district in Kerala?",
    "answerText": " Palakkad"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 88800,
    "questionText": " The largest and best preserved fort in Kerala?",
    "answerText": " Bakel"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 88801,
    "questionText": " The largest cardamom auction centre in Kerala?",
    "answerText": " Vandanmed"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 88802,
    "questionText": " The largest pass in Western ghats in Kerala?",
    "answerText": " Palghat"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 88803,
    "questionText": " The name of district existed when the Kerala state was formed and it is not existed at present?",
    "answerText": " Malabar"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 88804,
    "questionText": " The national park which is famous for Nilgiri Thar?",
    "answerText": " Iravikulam"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 88805,
    "questionText": " The old name of Sultan Bathery was?",
    "answerText": " Ganapativattom"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 88806,
    "questionText": " The oldest teak plantation in the world, Conolly’s plot is situated in the district of?",
    "answerText": " Malappuram"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 88807,
    "questionText": " The only district in Kerala that has no coastline and shares border with the districts of Kerala only?",
    "answerText": " Kottayam"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 88808,
    "questionText": " The only district in Kerala which produces garlic?",
    "answerText": " Idukki"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 88809,
    "questionText": " The only woman in the first EMS ministry?",
    "answerText": " KR Gowri"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 88810,
    "questionText": " The place famous for the manufacture of ‘Uru’?",
    "answerText": " Beppur"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 88811,
    "questionText": " The place in Idukky district where Indo-Swiss Project was established?",
    "answerText": " Mattuppetty"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 88812,
    "questionText": " The place in Kerala famous for orange farms?",
    "answerText": " Nelliyampathy"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 88813,
    "questionText": " The place in Kerala where Mannathu Padmabhan started the historical ‘Savarna jatha’?",
    "answerText": " Vaikom"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 88814,
    "questionText": " The place in Kerala where Public Library was established for the first time?",
    "answerText": " Thiruvananthapuram"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 88815,
    "questionText": " The place in Thiruvananthapuram district where the remains of ‘Ammachi Plavu’ in Travancore history is preserved?",
    "answerText": " Neyyatinkara"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 88816,
    "questionText": " The place Indo-Swiss Project started in 1963?",
    "answerText": " Mattuppetty"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 88817,
    "questionText": " The place known as ‘the Kashmir of Kerala’?",
    "answerText": " Munnar"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 88818,
    "questionText": " The place known as ‘Thekkan Kasi’?",
    "answerText": " Thirunelli"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 88819,
    "questionText": " The place where Cricket was played for the first time in Kerala?",
    "answerText": " Thalassery"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 88820,
    "questionText": " The place where Kumaranasan was born?",
    "answerText": " Kayikkara"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 88821,
    "questionText": " The place where the first Ayurvedic Medical College in Kerala was established?",
    "answerText": " Thiruvananthapuram"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 88822,
    "questionText": " The place where the first Law college in Kerala was established?",
    "answerText": " Thiruvananthapuram"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 88823,
    "questionText": " The place where the first under pass in Kerala was established?",
    "answerText": " Thiruvananthapuram"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 88824,
    "questionText": " The place which is known as the ‘cultural capital of Pathanamthitta’?",
    "answerText": " Aranmula"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 88825,
    "questionText": " The publication of Mathrubhumi newspaper was started from?",
    "answerText": " Kozhikode"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 88826,
    "questionText": " The remains of Sister Alphonsa is kept at?",
    "answerText": " Bharananganam"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 88827,
    "questionText": " The southernmost fresh water lagoon in Kerala is?",
    "answerText": " Vellayani"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 88828,
    "questionText": " The Thattekkad sanctuary is named after?",
    "answerText": " Salim Ali"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 88829,
    "questionText": " The venue of ‘Revathy Patathanam’ by Zamorin?",
    "answerText": " Thali Temple; Kozhikode"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 88830,
    "questionText": " Uzhavur, he birth place of KR Narayanan is in the district of?",
    "answerText": " Kottayam"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 88831,
    "questionText": " Where is Govinda Pai Memorial?",
    "answerText": " Mancheswaram"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 88832,
    "questionText": " Where is Putharikandam ground situated?",
    "answerText": " Thiruvananthapuram"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 88833,
    "questionText": " Which area was known as ‘Goshree’ in ancient days?",
    "answerText": " Kochi"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 88834,
    "questionText": " Which is known as the ‘Cultural capital of Kerala’?",
    "answerText": " Thrissur"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 88835,
    "questionText": " Which is known as ‘the gift of Pamba’?",
    "answerText": " Kuttanad"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 88836,
    "questionText": " Which is known as ‘the queen of the Arabian sea’?",
    "answerText": " Kochi"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 88837,
    "questionText": " Which is known as ‘the Venice of the East’?",
    "answerText": " Alappuzha"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 88838,
    "questionText": " Which is the birth place of Kathakali?",
    "answerText": " Kottarakkara"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 88839,
    "questionText": " Which palace is called ‘Mural Pagoda’?",
    "answerText": " Krishnapuram Palace"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 88840,
    "questionText": " Which place in Kasargod district was known as ‘Madathumala’ in ancient times?",
    "answerText": " Ranipuram"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 88841,
    "questionText": " Which place is known as the birth place of Ottan Thullal?",
    "answerText": " Ambalappuzha"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 88842,
    "questionText": " Which river is also known as ‘Tejaswini’?",
    "answerText": " Kariangode"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 88843,
    "questionText": " Which river is also known by the name Nila or Perar?",
    "answerText": " Bharatappuzha"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 88844,
    "questionText": " Which was known as ‘Desinganad’ in earlier days?",
    "answerText": " Kollam"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 88845,
    "questionText": " Which was known as ‘Odanad’ in earlier days?",
    "answerText": " Kayamkulam"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 88846,
    "questionText": " Which was known as ‘Taxilla of South India’?",
    "answerText": " Parthivapuram Sala"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 88847,
    "questionText": " Who became the first president of Travancore Communist Party ?",
    "answerText": " KC George"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 88848,
    "questionText": " Who was known as Kerala Krushchev?",
    "answerText": " MN Govindan Nair"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 88849,
    "questionText": " Who was the first minister in charge of Forest?",
    "answerText": " KC George"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 88850,
    "questionText": " Who was the first minister in charge of local self government?",
    "answerText": " PK Chathan Master"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 88851,
    "questionText": " Who was the first transport minister in Kerala?",
    "answerText": " TV Thomas"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 88852,
    "questionText": " Who was the minister in charge of Employment in the first EMS ministry?",
    "answerText": " TV Thomas"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 88853,
    "questionText": " Who was the secretary of Radical Group formed in Travancore?",
    "answerText": " MN Govindan Nair"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 88854,
    "questionText": " The largest archeological museum in Kerala is functioning at?",
    "answerText": " Hill Palace Tripunithura"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 88855,
    "questionText": " The official residence of Dewan of Travancore which later became the seat of Akasavani in Kerala?",
    "answerText": " Bhakti Vilasom"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 88856,
    "questionText": " Where is Krishnapuram Palace?",
    "answerText": " Kayamkulam"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 88857,
    "questionText": " Which is written by Thakazhi?",
    "answerText": " Ormayude Theerangalil"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 88858,
    "questionText": " Who introduced secretarial system in Travancore?",
    "answerText": " Colonel Monroe"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 88859,
    "questionText": " Who was appointed by the Govt of Travancore in 1934 to examine the matter of appointment to Govt Services?",
    "answerText": " G.D.Knox"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 88860,
    "questionText": " Who was entrusted by Marthanda Varma for making appointment to Govt Departments?",
    "answerText": " Ramayyan"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 88861,
    "questionText": " The European power that constructed Chaliyam Fort?",
    "answerText": " The Portuguese"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 88862,
    "questionText": " The first palace built in oriental style by the Westerners in India?",
    "answerText": " Mattanchery Palace"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 88863,
    "questionText": " The king of Travancore who issued a proclamation in 1874 to control nepotism in appointments to Govt Services?",
    "answerText": " Ayilyam Tirunal"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 88864,
    "questionText": " The king who was the first in the history of Travancore to establish a systematic administration?",
    "answerText": " Marthanda Varma"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 88865,
    "questionText": " The largest Fort in kerala?",
    "answerText": " Bakel"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 88866,
    "questionText": " The Viceroy who built Angel Fort?",
    "answerText": " Alphonso De Almeida"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 88867,
    "questionText": " What was the basic unit of the administration of Marthanda Varma?",
    "answerText": " Village"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 88868,
    "questionText": " Which Fort in kerala was also known as Fort William?",
    "answerText": " Chettuva Fort"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 88869,
    "questionText": " Which fort was described as ‘Cannon pointed towards the neck of Zamorin’?",
    "answerText": " Chalium Fort"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 88870,
    "questionText": " Who gave permission to built the Anchengo Fort in 1690?",
    "answerText": " Rani of Attingal"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 88871,
    "questionText": " Who seized the Fort Angel in 1663?",
    "answerText": " The Dutch"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 88872,
    "questionText": " Who was appointed by Marthanda Varma to regularise the tax system in Travancore?",
    "answerText": " Mallan Sankaran"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 88873,
    "questionText": " The oldest palace built by the Dutch in India?",
    "answerText": " Bolghatty Palace"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 88874,
    "questionText": " The only No-confidence motion passed in the history of Kerala brought the state under President’s rule for the second time was moved by?",
    "answerText": " P.K.Kunj"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 88875,
    "questionText": " The President’s rule was imposed for the second time in kerala in ?",
    "answerText": 1964
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 88876,
    "questionText": " The ruler of Kochi who introduced a regular administrative machinery for the first time?",
    "answerText": " Sakthan Thampuran"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 88877,
    "questionText": " Where is Sakthan Thampuran Museum?",
    "answerText": " Thrissur"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 88878,
    "questionText": " Which was the only state under President’s rule when the linguistic reorganisation was done?",
    "answerText": " Kerala"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 88879,
    "questionText": " Who constructed the Bolghatty Palace?",
    "answerText": " The Dutch"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 88880,
    "questionText": " Who recommended for declaring President’s rule in Thiru kochi when Panampally resigned in 1956?",
    "answerText": " Sri Chithira Tirunal"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 88881,
    "questionText": " Who was the acting Governor of kerala when the state was formed on 1st November,1956?",
    "answerText": " P.S.Rao"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 88882,
    "questionText": " Who was the first Public Service Commissioner appointed in Travancore?",
    "answerText": " G.D.Knox"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 88883,
    "questionText": " Who wrote ‘Adukkalayilninnu Parliamentilekk’ ?",
    "answerText": " Bharati Udayabhanu"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 88884,
    "questionText": " Who wrote ‘Ente Katha’?",
    "answerText": " Madhavikkutty"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 88885,
    "questionText": " Who wrote ‘Thudikkunna Thalukal’ ?",
    "answerText": " Changampuzha"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 88886,
    "questionText": " ‘Ente Natakasmarnakal’ is the autobiography of?",
    "answerText": " PJ Antony"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 88887,
    "questionText": " ‘Ente Vazhiyambalangal’ is the autobiography of?",
    "answerText": " SK Pottakkad"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 88888,
    "questionText": " In which year Malayali Memorial demanding the appointment of native people submitted?",
    "answerText": 1891
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 88889,
    "questionText": " Name the agitation that prompted the Govt of Travancore to appoint a Public Service Commissioner?",
    "answerText": " Abstention Movement"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 88890,
    "questionText": " Name the European power that built Angel Fort?",
    "answerText": " The Portugese"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 88891,
    "questionText": " The Angel Fort is situated at?",
    "answerText": " Kannur"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 88892,
    "questionText": " The British got Angel Fort from?",
    "answerText": " Arakkal Beevi"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 88893,
    "questionText": " Which palace is also known as ‘Dutch Palace’?",
    "answerText": " Mattanchery Palace"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 88894,
    "questionText": " Who built the Palakkad Fort in1766?",
    "answerText": " Hyder Ali"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 88895,
    "questionText": " Who constructed Bakel Fort in 17th century?",
    "answerText": " Sivappa Nayak"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 88896,
    "questionText": " Who constructed Chettuva Fort?",
    "answerText": " The Dutch"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 88897,
    "questionText": " Who constructed the Anchengo Fort?",
    "answerText": " The British"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 88898,
    "questionText": " Who was the President when President’s rule was imposed for the first time in Kerala?",
    "answerText": " Dr.Rajendraprasad"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 88899,
    "questionText": " The Liberation Struggle lasted for ...... weeks?",
    "answerText": 7
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 88900,
    "questionText": " At the time of the formation of the Kerala State, it has been under President’s rule for .......days?",
    "answerText": 155
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 88901,
    "questionText": " The only occasion in Kerala history in which none of the political parties could form a government after the election and President’s rule continued in the State?",
    "answerText": 1965
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 88902,
    "questionText": " Central Institute of Fisheries Technology (CIFT) is situated at?",
    "answerText": " Kochi"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 88903,
    "questionText": " Hindustan Newsprint Factory is situated at?",
    "answerText": " Velloor"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 88904,
    "questionText": " In which palace, mural paintings based on Kumarasambhava of Kalidasa can be seen?",
    "answerText": " Dutch Palace"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 88905,
    "questionText": " In which year Kerala Public Service Commission was formed?",
    "answerText": 1956
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 88906,
    "questionText": " Kerala Wood Industries is situated at?",
    "answerText": " Nilambur"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 88907,
    "questionText": " The lengthiest President’s rule in kerala was ended in?",
    "answerText": 1967
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 88908,
    "questionText": " The mouth piece of CPI Kerala unit?",
    "answerText": " Janayugam"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 88909,
    "questionText": " The number of Members in Kerala PSC including Chairman?",
    "answerText": 21
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 88910,
    "questionText": " The oldest European fort in India was built by?",
    "answerText": " The Portuguese"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 88911,
    "questionText": " Kerala became the first fully literate state in India in the year?",
    "answerText": 1991
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 88912,
    "questionText": " Kerala Panchayat Raj Act was brought into effect in Kerala in?",
    "answerText": 1994
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 88913,
    "questionText": " KSRTC was brought into existence in?",
    "answerText": 1965
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 88914,
    "questionText": " Madras Rubber Factory is at?",
    "answerText": " Vadavathoor"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 88915,
    "questionText": " PJ Antony got the Bharat Award in 1973 for the performance in the film?",
    "answerText": " Nirmalyam"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 88916,
    "questionText": " The country assisted for the construction of Idukky Dam completed in 1974, which is the first arch dam in India?",
    "answerText": " Canada"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 88917,
    "questionText": " The finance minister of Kerala who was instrumental in the launching of lottery in Kerala?",
    "answerText": " PK Kunju"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 88918,
    "questionText": " The first district in Kerala where DPEP was implemented in 1994?",
    "answerText": " Malappuram"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 88919,
    "questionText": " The first finance commission of Kerala was formed in?",
    "answerText": 1994
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 88920,
    "questionText": " The first hydel project in Malabar area started in 1972?",
    "answerText": " Kuttiadi"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 88921,
    "questionText": " Malabar Cement Factory is at?",
    "answerText": " Valayar"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 88922,
    "questionText": " Naval Academy is situated at?",
    "answerText": " Ezhimala"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 88923,
    "questionText": " Srimulam Assembly was started functioning in?",
    "answerText": 1904
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 88924,
    "questionText": " The first to make forts built in granite in Kerala history?",
    "answerText": " The Portuguese"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 88925,
    "questionText": " The Ananthavilasom Palace in Thiruvananthapuram was constructed during the reign of?",
    "answerText": " Visakham Tirunal"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 88926,
    "questionText": " The channel launched by CPM in Kerala?",
    "answerText": " Kairali"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 88927,
    "questionText": " The European power that built kottappuram fort in 1524?",
    "answerText": " The Portugese"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 88928,
    "questionText": " Travancore Cement Factory is situated at?",
    "answerText": " Nattakom"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 88929,
    "questionText": " Where is Napier Museum in Kerala?",
    "answerText": " Thiruvananthapuram"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 88930,
    "questionText": " Which Palace in Thiruvananthapuram is the venue of Swati Music Festival?",
    "answerText": " Kuthiramalika"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 88931,
    "questionText": " Who constructed Kanakakkunnu Palace?",
    "answerText": " Sri Mulam Tirunal"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 88932,
    "questionText": " Who constructed Mattancherry Palace?",
    "answerText": " The Portuguese"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 88933,
    "questionText": " Who led Communist Party of India(CPI) in Kerala after the split?",
    "answerText": " MN Govindan Nair"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 88934,
    "questionText": " Who was the editor of Vivekodayam started publication in 1905 as the mouth piece of the SNDP Yogam?",
    "answerText": " Kumaranasan"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 88935,
    "questionText": " Who was the first secretary of the SNDP Yogam, formed in 1903?",
    "answerText": " Kumaranasan"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 88936,
    "questionText": " Who was the Governor of kerala when President’s rule was imposed for the first time in Kerala?",
    "answerText": " B.RamakrishnaRao"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 88937,
    "questionText": " Who was the last Chief Minister of Thiru KOchi whose resignation led to president’s rule?",
    "answerText": " Panampilly Govinda Menon"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 88938,
    "questionText": " Legislative body in the princely state of Cochin started functioning in?",
    "answerText": 1925
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 88939,
    "questionText": " A popular ministry under Pattom Thanu Pillai assumed power in Travancore in?",
    "answerText": 1948
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 88940,
    "questionText": " Chattampi Swamikal passed away at Panmana in Kollam district in?",
    "answerText": 1924
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 88941,
    "questionText": " Cochin Port Trust was brought into existence in?",
    "answerText": 1964
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 88942,
    "questionText": " CP Ramaswamy Iyer became the Dewan of Travancore in?",
    "answerText": 1936
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 88943,
    "questionText": " Eravikulam ,the first national park in Kerala was brought into existence in?",
    "answerText": 1978
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 88944,
    "questionText": " Kerala Sangeetha Nataka Academy was established in?",
    "answerText": 1958
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 88945,
    "questionText": " KPAC (Kerala People’s Arts Club) was formed in?",
    "answerText": 1951
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 88946,
    "questionText": " Malayalam television programmes were started from Thiruvananthapuram in?",
    "answerText": 1985
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 88947,
    "questionText": " Mayyazhi was liberated from the French rule in?",
    "answerText": 1954
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 88948,
    "questionText": " Name the first ship built at Cochin shipyard in 1980?",
    "answerText": " Rani Padmini"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 88949,
    "questionText": " Panampilly Govindamenon became the prime minister of Cochin in?",
    "answerText": 1947
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 88950,
    "questionText": " Radio station in Thiruvananthapuram was started functioning in?",
    "answerText": 1943
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 88951,
    "questionText": " Sarada got national award for best actor in 1968 for the film?",
    "answerText": " Thulabharam"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 88952,
    "questionText": " Telecasting was started from Thiruvananthapuram in?",
    "answerText": 1982
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 88953,
    "questionText": " The Cochin Stock Exchange was established in?",
    "answerText": 1978
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 88954,
    "questionText": " The Cochin University was brought into existence in?",
    "answerText": 1971
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 88955,
    "questionText": " The first movie in Kerala- Vigathakumaran was released in?",
    "answerText": 1928
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 88956,
    "questionText": " The Kerala Press Academy was established in 1979 with ..... as its headquarters?",
    "answerText": " Kochi"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 88957,
    "questionText": " The Kerala Sashtra Sahitya Parishad was formed at Kozhikode in?",
    "answerText": 1962
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 88958,
    "questionText": " The King Srimulam Tirunal of Travancore passed away in?",
    "answerText": 1924
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 88959,
    "questionText": " The Sahithya Pravarthaka Sahakarana Sangham started functioning based on Kottayam in?",
    "answerText": 1945
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 88960,
    "questionText": " The second university of Kerala, the Calicut University was started fuctioning in?",
    "answerText": 1968
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 88961,
    "questionText": " The year of Punnapra Vayalar agitation?",
    "answerText": 1946
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 88962,
    "questionText": " Thumba Rocket launching station was started funtioning in?",
    "answerText": 1963
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 88963,
    "questionText": " To which organisation, Thumba Rocket Launching Station was dedicated in 1968?",
    "answerText": " UNO"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 88964,
    "questionText": " Travacore and Cochin were integrated in?",
    "answerText": 1949
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 88965,
    "questionText": " Udaya, the first film studio in Kerala was started funtioning at Alapuzha in?",
    "answerText": 1948
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 88966,
    "questionText": " Who became the Chief Minister in TravancoreCochin after the first general election?",
    "answerText": " AJ John"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 88967,
    "questionText": " Who became the first Chairman of the Kerala Sahitya Academy in 1956?",
    "answerText": " Sardar KM Panicker"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 88968,
    "questionText": " Who established Kerala Kalamandalam at Cheruthuruthy in 1930?",
    "answerText": " Vallathol Narayana Menon"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 88969,
    "questionText": " Who got the first Odakkuzhal Award instituted by G.Sankara Kurup?",
    "answerText": " Vennikkulam"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 88970,
    "questionText": " Who pointed out the importance of Thattekkad for the first time which became a sanctuary in 1983?",
    "answerText": " Salim Ali"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 88971,
    "questionText": " Who was the first director of the Kerala Language Institute founded in 1968?",
    "answerText": " NV Krishna Varrier"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 88972,
    "questionText": " Who was the last chief minister of TravancoreCochin ?",
    "answerText": " Panampilly Govindamenon"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 88973,
    "questionText": " Who was the main leader of salt satyagraha in Kerala, which was organised as part of Civil Disobedience movement?",
    "answerText": " K Kelappan"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 88974,
    "questionText": " Who wrote the first detective novel in MalayalamBhaskaramenon in 1924?",
    "answerText": " Appan Thampuran"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 88975,
    "questionText": " Adoor Gopalakrishnan got national award for best director in 1972 for his first feature film?",
    "answerText": " Swayamvaram"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 88976,
    "questionText": " EMS became the chief minister of Kerala for the second time in the year?",
    "answerText": 1967
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 88977,
    "questionText": " G Sankarakurup got the first Gyanpeet Award for ‘Odakkuzhal’ for the year?",
    "answerText": 1965
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 88978,
    "questionText": " In which district is the headquarters of Kottakkal Arya Vaidhya Sala?",
    "answerText": " Malappuram"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 88979,
    "questionText": " In which district is Vallarpadam Container Terminal?",
    "answerText": " Ernakulam"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 88980,
    "questionText": " In which year Kerala won Santosh Trophy for the first time?",
    "answerText": 1973
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 88981,
    "questionText": " The European power that renovated Mattancherry Palace?",
    "answerText": " The Dutch"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 88982,
    "questionText": " The first chairman of Kerala Public Service Commission?",
    "answerText": " V.K.Velayudhan"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 88983,
    "questionText": " The first EMS ministry ruled for....... months?",
    "answerText": 28
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 88984,
    "questionText": " The first European fort in India was built at?",
    "answerText": " Kochi"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 88985,
    "questionText": " The head office of Kerala Public Service Commission is at?",
    "answerText": " Thiruvananthapuram"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 88986,
    "questionText": " The King of Travancore who constructed the ‘Puthan Malika’ or ‘Kuthira Malika’ in Thiruvananthapuram?",
    "answerText": " Swati Tirunal"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 88987,
    "questionText": " The Koyikkal Palace where Numismatics Museum is functioning is situated at?",
    "answerText": " Nedumangad"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 88988,
    "questionText": " The first MLA to be disqualified under the antidefection law in 1990?",
    "answerText": " R Balakrishna Pillai"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 88989,
    "questionText": " The first private channel in Kerala which started functioning in 1993?",
    "answerText": " Asianet"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 88990,
    "questionText": " The foundation of the first biological park in India was laid in 1992 at?",
    "answerText": " Agasthyarkutam"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 88991,
    "questionText": " The headquarters of Central university in Kerala?",
    "answerText": " Kazargod"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 88992,
    "questionText": " The headquarters of the Mahathma Gandhi University is situated at?",
    "answerText": " Athirampuzha"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 88993,
    "questionText": " The Kerala State Electricity Board was established in?",
    "answerText": 1957
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 88994,
    "questionText": " Where is Banana Research Centre?",
    "answerText": " Kannara"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 88995,
    "questionText": " Where is Cardomom Research Centre?",
    "answerText": " Pampadumpara"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 88996,
    "questionText": " Where is Centre for Development of Imaging Technology (C-DIT) is situated?",
    "answerText": " Thiruvananthapuram"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 88997,
    "questionText": " Where is Coffee Research Centre?",
    "answerText": " Choondal"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 88998,
    "questionText": " Where is Ginger Research Centre?",
    "answerText": " Ambalavayal"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 88999,
    "questionText": " The headquarters of Marketfed?",
    "answerText": " Kochi"
  },
  {
    "questionNum": 89000,
    "questionText": " Centre for Earth Science Studies (CESS)is at?",
    "answerText": " Thiruvananthapuram"
  }
]